What was going on there, huh?
想干嘛？
We thought you were sleeping, Daddy.
爸爸 我们以为你睡着了呢
How can I sleep with two Twinkie burglars roaming around?
两个小坏蛋晃来晃去的 我怎么睡得着
Can we watch Dragon Tales, please?
我们能看巨龙传说吗？
Yeah. Why not, why not?
当然可以 为什么不呢
Which one of these turns on the TV?
哪个是电视机的遥控器？
Honey, I think you just opened the garage.
亲爱的 我想你把车库的门打开了
I'm just planning ahead. I know.
我这是提前打开做准备
P-yew! Was that a stinky-dink bug? Good job.
哦 嘿 臭屁虫！ 真能干
Whatever happened to the good old days...
以前的日子多简单呀
...when you pulled the knob and on came the boob tube?
老电视机只要拉一下开关就开了
The O'Doyles got a universal remote control.
欧多雷家有个万能遥控器
One clicker controls everything.
点一下就能控制所有东西
Makes life a lot easier for old people like you.
尤其适合你这样的老人 真方便
Well, whoop-de-do for the O'Doyles.
哦 都在说欧多雷家
Tree house?
树上小屋？
I don't know. Ask your father.
我也不知道 问你爸爸吧
Ask me what?
问我什么？
Do you think you'll have time to finish building the tree house ever?
你会有时间帮我们完成那个树屋吗
Yeah, Dad. It's kind of been halfway done for two months now.
对呀 老爸 那半成品挂在树上都两个月啦
All right. I want to, it's just I got a lot of things going on at work right now.
嗯 我也想尽快 只是我现在手头事情太多
But as soon as I'm done, I'm on it. I promise. Hang in there.
但我保证 只要一有空 我就去盖屋 等着吧
Hey, look at Sundance wrestle his duck.
快瞧 阳阳在和鸭子摔交呢
Oh, no, that's not wrestling.
哦 不 那不是摔交 那是
That's something you shouldn't know about for another 10 to 30 years.
再过10到30年后你们就会懂了
Ten for you. Thirty for you.
你再10年 你再30年
Hey, Michael? I'll see you tonight at the swim meet?
迈可 今晚游泳赛你来吗
Swim meet.
游泳赛？
I gotta go to that? Yes.
我得去？ 对呀
I'm kidding you. I'll be there. Okay? All right. I love you, Michael.
开玩笑的 我会去的 好吗 嗯 我爱你 迈可
Forever and ever, babe.
一生一世 宝贝
Mr. Newman.
纽曼先生
Kevin O'Doyle. Yeah. Always a pleasure.
凯文・欧多雷 很高兴见到你
What kind of stereo you got in that blue piece of shit?
你那破车里的音响是什么牌的？
You know what? I never checked, Kevin.
这个嘛 我倒没注意过
Yeah, well, my father's stereo is a Bose.
哦 恩 我爸的音响是博斯(Bose)
Your father's stereo blows? That's too bad.
你爸的音响“破死”了？ 真可怜
No! I said... That's not what I said!
不！ 我是说 我没那样说！
His father's stereo blows!
他爸的音响“破死”了！
Come on! Pay the man, let's go!
得了 给那老兄点钱吧！
Good morning, Mr. Newman. Good morning.
早安 纽曼先生 早安
Good morning, Mr. Newman. Hello.
你好
Good morning, Mr. Newman. Hi.
早安 纽曼先生
Good morning, Mr. Newman. Man, Alice...
爱丽丝 你好
...I was stuck in traffic for an hour and a half. When's the meeting?
塞车塞了一个半小时 会议是几点
It started already. What?
呃 已经开始了 什么？
Can I go to the bathroom?
我能去上厕所吗？
Go to the bathroom. I told you, you don't have to ask me.
去吧 我告诉过你 不用请示我
Well, the interesting thing, Prince Habeeboo...
哈比布王子 有趣的是
...is that the building codes in Manhattan will allow us...
曼哈顿的建筑法规只准我们
Michael. Sorry I'm late, sir.
迈可 对不起 我迟到了
Some moron in a red Lamborghini parked in my spot so...
不知哪个猪头的红色兰博基尼 停在了我的车位 所以
Prince Habeeboo drive red Lamborghini.
哈比布王子开的是红色兰博基尼
Red Lamborghini? I meant blue Ferrari.
红色兰博基尼？ 我是说蓝色法拉利
Is this one of your partners?
他是 你的合伙人之一吗
Actually, Michael is just an associate.
实际上 迈可只是公司的同仁
But he is one of our brightest young architects.
但他是我最年轻有为的建筑师之一
Thank you.
谢谢
Walk His Majesty through our design concept.
给殿下解释一下你的设计理念
With pleasure.
我的荣幸
Prince Haboobee... Habeeboo!
哈布比王子 哈比布！
Prince Habeeboo.
王子哈比布
Habeeboo. I thought I said that.
哈比布 我没说错呀
When Mr. Ammer explained to me the type of man you are...
当安莫先生告诉我 您是一位
...a visionary who prides himself on originality...
为自己原创理念而骄傲的人
...I said to myself, "Let's smash the mold and redefine elegance."
所以我想 让我们抛弃老套 为典雅重新定义
So I present to you your restaurant.
容我为您展示 您的餐厅
Where is... Where's bar?
酒吧在在哪里？
Bar is... Here's the bar. Now, the waterfall...
酒吧在这儿 然后这个是瀑布
Make bar longer.
把酒吧加长点儿
Okay. We could cut into the atrium a little bit.
好吧 我们可以朝中亭切进一点
No atrium. Just make bar longer for Prince Habeeboo.
不要中庭 只要为哈比布王子 把酒吧加长就行了
Really?
真的吗？
Still itchy? You got it.
还痒吗？ 行了
And put big drain in floor for wet T-shirt contest.
为了湿T恤比赛 地板上要设置大排水孔
Now, you're kidding me, right?
您不是开玩笑吧
Boob water's gotta go someplace, Michael.
废水总得要有处排吧 迈可
Let's just take out the atrium and run with that and there's your drain.
就把中庭拿掉 然后这样 这就是排水孔啦
God. I love it. It is simply awesome.
天啊 我喜欢 酷毙了
Yeah. Basically you want me to design you an Arabian hoochie house?
是的 基本上您要我设计 一个阿拉伯肚皮舞厅？
How dare you compare Prince Habeeboo's Bikini Hut...
你怎么能把哈比布王子 的比基尼小屋
...to this hoochie house? This idea's...
比做妓院？ 这想法
...got nothing to do with hoochies, Michael.
跟妓院没关系 迈克
It's like opposite of hoochie.
与妓院正相反
No disrespect, Prince Hubbida Hubbida.
我没有冒犯您的意思 哈比达哈比达王子
Hubba Bubba. Habeeboo!
哈巴巴巴 哈比布！
Habeeboo! Hubba Bubba is chewing gum.
哈比布！ 哈巴巴巴是口香糖
Prince Habeeboo's not chewing gum.
哈比布王子可不是口香糖
Prince Habeeboo, we will... I will make this happen.
哈比布王子 我们会 我会完全照办
John Ammer's office.
约翰・安莫办公室
I hope that atrium idea didn't take too long to configure, Michael.
希望你别在中庭的事上 浪费太长时间 迈可
Oh, there'll be other Junes in my life, sir.
很快就搞定了 没事的
See that parking garage over there on 56?
看到那个56街上的停车场吗？
Watsuhita wants to knock it down and build a luxury hotel.
和津 想要拆了它 用那块地来盖高级旅馆
You got the commission? Not yet.
你拿到手了吗？ 还没
I just need someone to come up with a design proposal. Intrigued?
我需要有人设计一个设计企划书 有兴趣吗
Hell, yes.
呵 当然有
I'm Fourth of July-ing with the kids. When I get back, I'm all over it.
国庆日我带孩子出门回来后 马上就开始
Great. Have a great Fourth of July with the kids. I'll put Swardson on it.
好极了 祝你和孩子们玩得愉快 我让斯沃森来做
No, no. Absolutely not. I... I... Can't it just wait three days?
不 不 别这样 难道就不能等三天
These guys are Japanese. They can't wait for their fish to cook.
那些家伙可是日本人 他们连等鱼煮熟的时间都没有
I guess I could talk to my wife.
我要先和老婆谈谈
Great. See you later at happy hour with Prince Habadabee.
很好 我们和王子一起去快活时见
My son has a swim meet tonight that I have to get to s...
晚上我儿子有游泳比赛 我得去
I'm just messing with you. We're good.
我只是开个玩笑 没问题的
Yeah, Ben!
好的 本！
That's my boy! That's my boy! Kid, you were great!
我的好孩子 好孩子 孩子 你真棒！
You're not my dad.
你不是我爸
As far as you know. What?
你知道什么 什么！？？
I was just joking.
开玩笑的
Is he really my dad?
他真的是我爸吗？
Come on, come on! Yes, Ben. Yes, you did it!
加油 加油 你成功了！
Honey, you were so great.
宝贝 你真行
Whoa, what are you, half a dolphin or something? That was incredible.
哇 你快成海豚了 不可思议！
You just got here, Dad. I saw you.
爸 你才到 我看见了
What do you mean I just got here? Why are you saying that?
哪有 你怎么这么说啊
I saw you. You jumped in there, you swam here.
我看见你从那儿跳下去 游到这儿
Then what stroke was he doing, Dad? He was doing the shut-up.
爸 那你说他游什么式呀？ 他游的是 你闭嘴式
Hey. Good thing is, Daddy was here to see you finish.
起码爸爸赶来看你游回终点了
He didn't see me finish.
他没看到
He was hanging out with Ping Woo for some reason.
不知道他刚在怎么在胡平那边
Yeah, what was that about, huh? The kid was drowning.
对呀 你刚在干嘛？ 那孩子快淹死了
I'm gonna let him drown?
难道我能袖手旁观吗？
Nobody goes drowning in my pool.
决不会有人淹死在我的池子里
How you doing? Bill Herlihy. Ben's coach. You must be Dad.
你好 我是比尔・赫利 游泳教练 你是他父亲吧
Michael Speedo... Michael Newman. Sorry.
我是迈可・斯比杜 对不起 是迈可・纽曼才对
Big Ben, that was great progress out there, huh?
好样的 本 进步神速啊
Just remember, right arm out, head turns left. Left arm out...
记住 右手出水 头就转左 左手出水
Head turns right. I know. I just forgot at the end.
头就转右 我知道 只是到最后忘了
Well, that's all right.
没关系
You master that, people are gonna think you're a half a dolphin out there.
掌握好了 你就成了半只海豚啦
Really? Yeah.
真的？ 真的
Cute.
真可爱
Hello? Mr. Ammer.
你好？ 安莫先生
Ben, honey, slow down. It's not a race.
本 亲爱的 吃慢点儿 这不是比赛
That's his second one in five minutes.
这是他五分钟内吃的第二个了
Keeps eating more and more.
还不停的再吃
He's like a machine. He can't still be hungry.
像台机器 他怎么还会饿呢
He's not. He's just doing whatever Michael's doing. It's driving me crazy.
他不是饿 他像迈可一样 老做些让我抓狂的事
Everything Michael's been doing lately is very unhealthy for him.
迈可最近做的事都很不利于健康
He's gonna kill himself.
他会杀了自己的
Like a signature building we're talking about.
就像我们讨论过的主体建筑
Oh, my God.
哦 天啊
Scared the crap out of me.
吓了我一大跳
Dad, how much longer are you gonna live?
爸爸 你还能活多久？
One minute. One minute?
等我一分钟 一分钟？
Daddy's gonna die in one minute! Oh, no, honey.
爹地一分钟后要死了！ 不 不 宝贝
Don't worry. I'm not dying.
别担心 我不会死的
I'm gonna live for 200 years. Is that long enough for you and me?
我会活两百年 对咱们俩来说够长了吧？
Promise? I promise. Swear. Come here.
保证？ 我发誓 甜心 过来抱抱
You son of a bitch!
你们这些婊子养的！
Hey! There are families here!
喂 这儿有小孩啊！
Show some respect, you pieces of shit!
放尊重点儿 狗屎！
Go home and watch VH1, old man.
老头儿 回家看VH1吧
Don't light another damn one!
不准再放他妈的一炮！
Benjamin. Benjamin. What am I holding?
本杰明 本杰明 我手上拿的什么？
A quarter. Now, Grandma does not let me eat ice cream...
两角五分的硬币 姥姥不准我吃冰激淋
...because of my diabetes. True.
因为我有糖尿病 没错
But she says nothing, however, about a tasty quarter.
但她可没说不准吃个美味的硬币
Okay.
好吧
All right. All right.
好啦 好啦
Very quickly, please, count to three because it tastes terrible.
快数三 因为硬币好难吃
One, two, three.
一、二、三
Are you shitting me?
真他妈得唬人
First he's eating like his father, now you're talking like him?
他先是吃相像他爸 现在连说话口气都像啦？
Ben. Don't you ever say that again.
本 以后不准再说脏话
Sorry, Grandma. How do you do that, Grandpa?
对不起 奶奶 你是怎么变的 爷爷？
A good magician never reveals his secrets.
好魔术师决不泄漏秘密
Your daddy has wanted to know how I've done that trick...
你爸从你这年纪起
...since he was your age.
就想知道我这把戏的秘密
Isn't that true, son?
对吧 儿子？
Hey, Michael. Michael, who are you talking to?
喂 迈可 和谁说话呢？
Jesus. I'm talking to my boss, Ma. Take it easy.
天啊 老妈 在跟老板说话 别紧张
Oh, yeah? Well, tell him to get a life.
哦 是吗？ 好吧 告诉他自个儿找乐子去
You got family here. You're busy. Come on.
全家都到了 而你忙得很 来吧
My mother says hello.
我妈向你问好
Oh, he's such a big boy, isn't he?
他已经是个大人了 对吗？
On his big cell phone. Big boy.
打手机的样子 很人模人样
That's it. Get some sleep. Thank you, Mr. Ammer. All right. Good night.
就这样 晚安 谢谢 安莫先生 好的 晚安
Are you done? Can we relax now? Sorry.
你忙完了 我们可以轻松一下了吧？ 对不起
Eat me, grandpa!
来呀 老爷爷！
You're dead.
你死定了
Oh, shit! Yeah, you better run!
糟啦！ 没错 你们最好赶快跑
I kicked your father's ass in high school!
高中时 我就踹过你老子的屁股！
Now I'm gonna kick yours!
现在该你们了！
I hate that man.
我讨厌那个人
Okay, good night, you two cowboys.
晚安 小牛仔们
Reach for the sky, Pocahontas. No, back to bed.
摸摸天空 波卡洪塔斯 不 回去睡觉
Come on. Pocahontas is off duty. I'm out of here.
快去睡 波卡洪塔斯下班了 我也要走了
You getting sick, sheriff?
你病啦 治安官
I don't got time to be sick, so no.
不 我没时间生病
I need to watch this documentary on Asian architecture.
我还得看亚洲建筑纪录片
Well, you gotta get some rest sometime, sweetheart.
甜心 你总得休息吧
Besides, the woodland creatures will laugh at you...
如果你病恹恹的 周末去露营
...if you collapse trying to put up the tent this weekend.
森林里的动物会笑你
Yeah. I forgot to tell you.
啊 忘了跟你说
We gotta postpone the camping trip.
我们得把露营的时间延后
Ammer put me on a project.
安莫给了我个计划
It's due Tuesday. If I don't finish, I'm off it, so...
下星期二前得完成 否则就的让人了
The kids have been talking about camping all year.
但孩子们一整年都在盼着和你露营
Think I don't know that?
你觉得我不知道吗？
It's just every choice I make, everything I do...
不管我怎么决定 不管我做了什么事
...I disappoint somebody.
都会让某些人失望
Make sure you don't keep disappointing the wrong people.
所以你别让不该失望的人失望
I'm not out drinking or gambling or hitting on chicks.
我又不是吃喝嫖赌
I'm working my ass off so my family can have a better life...
而是拼命工作让我家人
...than I dreamed of when I was a kid.
过上我儿时梦想的生活
The only way for that to happen is for me to watch this stinking show!
要实现梦想 我就得看这无聊的录相！
So relax, hon.
饶了我吧 亲爱的
Are you kidding me?
你开玩笑吗？
Will you give me a break one time?
什么时候能才放过我？
Damn it! The O'Doyles got a stinking universal remote control.
妈的 欧多雷有万能遥控器
We're gonna have one too.
我们也要一个
I'm sick of this.
我受够了
You want me to open the garage for you?
要我替你开车库门吗？
Closed.
打烊了
Open.
开着
Bed Bath & Beyond it is.
卧浴与超越
Hey, man?
你好
You guys got any universal remote controls in there?
你们有万能遥控器吗？
For a shower curtain or a bathmat? For a television.
浴室窗帘还是地垫用的？ 电视用的
I don't think so. Maybe for a blanket?
没有了 毯子用的怎么样？
You got a remote for a blanket?
毯子还有遥控器？
Sorry, I don't work here. I'm waiting for my friends.
对不起 我不是这的员工 我在等我朋友
You're kidding me.
你开玩笑吧？
Actually, yes. I don't have any friends. Will you be my friend?
是的 我根本没朋友 你能做我的朋友吗？
Wow, man.
哇 老兄！
Bed. Bed.
床 床
Bath. Bath.
浴室 浴室
Bed.
床
So tired of my life.
活的真累
Beyond?
超越？
Sorry to sneak up on you. I just...
对不起 我不请自来
You guys got a universal remote control back here?
你们这儿有万能遥控器吗？
Something stinks like stale french fries.
有过期薯条的臭味
All right, that's probably me.
呵 那多半是我
You know, fast food shortens your life.
你知道快餐会让你短命的吧
Yeah, that's what I heard.
是的 我听说了
But the way my life's been going lately, that ain't such a bad thing.
不过以我目前的处境来说 还不错
You're looking for a universal remote control?
你要找万能遥控器？
Yeah. Just one device to do it all for me...
对 一个遥控器 能控制所有电器
...make my life a little easier, quicker, not so damn complicated.
让我能活得舒服些 别那么复杂
I'm not supposed to do this, but you seem like a good guy.
我本不该帮你 不过你像是个好人
Hey. Somebody noticed. Thank you.
嘿 还有人会注意到 谢谢
I'm gonna show you a remote we just got in...
我带你去看刚进的遥控器
...that's probably the most advanced piece of technology...
是这儿最先进的
...we have in this place.
科技产品
Sounds sweet. It is sweet.
听起来不错 确实不错
The latest, greatest universal remote not even on the market yet.
当然了 最新最先进 还没上市呢
I guess the O'Doyles' remote can bite my advanced-technological ass then.
我猜欧多雷的遥控器是小巫见大巫了
I don't know the O'Doyles...
我不认识欧多雷 但
...but they can bite it hard.
它那遥控器差远了
Yeah.
好极了
Come in the back with me.
跟我到后面来
Okay.
好的
This is... This is very nice of you.
你可真是好人
What's your name, anyways? Call me Morty.
对了 你叫什么名字？ 就叫我莫蒂吧
Morty, I'm Michael Newman.
你好莫蒂 我是迈可・纽曼
Michael Newman.
迈可・纽曼
I'm about to rock your world.
我马上要颠覆你原来的世界了
Okay.
好的
I gotta be honest with you. This place looks bigger from the outside.
老实说 这地方从外面看还比较大
Just kidding.
玩笑啦
Hey, hey.
嘿 嘿
I think maybe there in the middle?
大概在中间？
Sneaky.
够狡猾的
Where's the box? Does it come with directions?
有盒子吗？ 有说明书么？
Not necessary.
没必要
Just point, click.
只要对着 按一下
Eventually, it will program itself.
其实它会自动设定
How much is this thing?
这要多少钱？
Because I ain't exactly Thurston Howell, you know?
我不是瑟斯顿・豪维尔
Lucky for you, it's not in the bar-code system yet.
你运气好 它还没有进条码库
So I'm gonna have to just give it to you.
所以我把它送给你啦
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What's the catch here, man?
呜 等等 该不会有诈吧？
Want me to take my shirt off for you? Because I don't play for that team.
你要我把外套留下？ 我可不吃你的把戏
Hey. Man, get out of here.
喂 快走了
Why are you doing this, then?
你为什么要这样做？
Because good guys need a break every once in a while.
因为好人时不时也该受老天眷顾吧
Take it.
拿上吧
Enjoy.
好好享受
All right.
好吧
Only one thing you need to know, Michael.
你只要记住一件事 迈克
This item is nonreturnable.
不能退货
Why would I wanna return something I got for free?
我干嘛要退不要钱的东西
Twinkie. You don't need it. You don't need it, man.
你不需要 不需要
You do need a Yodel, though. Okay. Good job.
你需要甜点
Let's see what you got, mate.
来试试怎么样
Look at me, turning my own TV on. I'm a freaking whiz kid.
看看 我居然能开我家的电视了 我真是个天才
Residential architecture...
住宅建筑…
So I talked to the kids. Oh, yeah?
我跟孩子们说了 哦 是吗？
They're very understanding about not going camping this weekend.
他们能理解周末不能去露营
Great. They could have a sleepover instead.
那好 我同意他们可以请朋友来过夜
That's a great idea. Thank you, thank you.
好主意 谢谢 谢谢
Thanks for being so cool about this too.
谢谢你这样冷静的处理这件事
Can I ask you something? Yes.
我能问你个问题吗？ 可以
After you do all this work and become a big player at your company...
你辛勤工作在公司成了大人物之后
...do you think you're gonna have more time for us...
你觉得会有更多时间陪我们
...or are things just gonna get even more out of control?
还是以后情况会失去控制？
Wait. When I get to that place and become a boss...
等等 等我成了老板
...a millionaire, a big shot, the first thing I'm gonna do...
百万富翁 大人物后第一件事就是
...is hire a bunch of idiots just like me to do all my work.
去雇一群像我这样的傻子替我工作
So then you, me and the kids can do whatever the hell we want.
然后 你 我 孩子们想干嘛就干嘛
You just gotta give me some time.
你只是得我一点儿时间
Don't give me that look.
别摆出那样得表情
I'm just saying, give me some support. All right?
我只是说 我需要你支持我
I love you. Go to sleep.
我爱你 去睡吧
Just think about it, Michael. Absolutely.
想想我的问题吧 迈可 当然
And stop with the Yodels.
别再吃甜点了
You're gonna wake up 400 pounds. Okay.
哪天睡醒 你会变400磅 好
Hey, hey, hey. Keep it down, dude. Everybody's sleeping.
喂 小声点儿 伙计 大家都在睡觉
You gotta poop again?
你又要拉屎了？
Why don't you do the humpy-pumpy on the duck, okay?
你去和鸭子摔角 好吗？
Will you just hold it in for five minutes and keep the freaking volume down?
再忍五分钟 给我小声点儿
I guess when you combine...
我猜当我把
...mass quantities of cough syrup with Yodels...
咳嗽糖浆加甜点
...you get acid.
就会产生幻觉
Go.
去
Hey, you said you gotta go. Go already, man.
你要大便 那就快去呀
Sniffy Longdroppings, today.
要拉就快拉
Holy motherfu!
天杀的…！
Yeah, I mean, you're right. In the short run...
你说得对 短期来说…
...plastic surgery is a hassle.
整容很不舒服
But six months later...
但六个月后…
...I'm gonna have a face and a body...
我就能拥有
...that's gonna get me to places where I wanna be.
让我想去哪就去哪的脸蛋和身材
Oh, my mother, typical, you know, she says:
我妈还是很老套 她说
"Oh, this procedure is too risky."
“这种手术很危险”
If Samantha wanted her cheekbones shaved down, I think I'd freak out too.
如果萨曼莎要把颧骨削档幕 也会吓死我的
I know, but I just think, you know, they're too Slavic.
我觉得他们太像斯拉夫人
You should get some work done.
你也该去整个容
Then maybe Michael will wanna hang out with you too.
这样也许迈可就会多陪陪你了
Morning, Michael. You're looking very crappy today.
早安 迈可 你今天真没精神
Morning, Janine, you're looking very Slavic.
早安 洁宁 你看起来很斯拉夫
You're just jealous because Donna and I are going to the gym...
你是忌妒我吧 我和唐娜要去健身
...and all the guys are gonna be hitting on us.
所有的男人都会过来搭讪
Michael knows he's my one and only.
哦 迈可知道他是我唯一的男人
Forever and ever, babe.
永远永远 宝贝
Sorry about last night. And I love you. I'm s...
昨晚对不起 我爱你
Oh, my God. I want that so bad.
噢 我也要一个
A husband that I can kiss and love and give juice to.
一个我能吻能爱的丈夫 还能把我的“果汁”给他的
You've already cheated on three different husbands with their brothers.
你和你前三任丈夫的兄弟都有一腿
I think you've given enough juice to everybody.
我想你给他们的汁可不少啊
Love juice.
爱汁
You know way too much about me.
你知道太多我的私事了
I should never have done that Montel Williams show.
我就知道不该上蒙托・威廉斯秀的
Even Montel Williams thinks you're crazy...
连蒙托都说你太疯狂
...and he's seen a lot of shit.
他看到一大堆狗屎
I was desperate for companionship!
我在交友上真是伤透心了！
All of my husbands...
我所有的丈夫
All of them have emotionally abandoned me.
我的前夫们在精神上都抛弃了我
They went to work. You had sex with their unemployed brothers.
他们都得去上班 然后你就 和他们下岗的兄弟上床
You're a horndog. Michael.
你也太淫荡了吧 迈可
Okay, sweetie. Calm it down. No, no!
别放心上 不要 不要！
I have had self-esteem issues since I was a kid.
我从小就有自尊心问题
I had a rabbit named Pepper. And that rabbit abandoned me too!
我以前养只兔子叫胡椒 连它都抛弃了我
Even the rabbit did! Even the rabb...
连兔子都…
Don't look at me!
别看着我
What's wrong with me? Bunny rabbit, bunny...
我咋了？ 小兔子 小兔子…
Here's the pitch to Matsui. A deep drive.
球向松井投出 球飞得好远
Oh, my, it's out of here!
哦 天 出去了！
A two-run shot into the right-field seats for Hideki Matsui.
打到右侧看台 松井打出全垒打
I'm sorry. What was that?
你刚说啥？
She has so many problems. Why do you have to be so mean?
她有一堆问题 你干嘛还对她这么刻薄
I don't know, I... Hello.
我也不知道怎么会那么说
I gotta go.
我得走了
Yeah, good RoboDog.
好 机器狗
And he can bark in over six different languages.
它还能用六种语言叫
It's so cool.
真酷
Yeah, it's much cooler than your stupid, human dog.
对呀 比你那条真的笨狗酷多了
Hey, Dad, see Kevin's new robot dog?
爸 看到凯文的机器狗了吗？
Yeah, yeah. Very nice.
嗯 还不错
"Very nice"? This thing is worth more than your car.
还不错！？  它比你的车还贵
Not anymore it ain't. RoboDog!
它不再是了 机器狗！
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿 嘿
Okay. Is this some sort of reality show? Are you the host?
这是不是真人秀啊？ 你是主持人？
Morty? Where are the cameras?
莫蒂？ 摄影机呢？
Got everybody in on it, huh? Sundance did very well also.
所有的人都上节目了吧 我的狗演得还不错
All right, America! Have your laugh! I'm an idiot!
哇！ 各位美国观众 笑吧 我是呆瓜
Donna, I'm gonna get you!
唐娜 我回头再找你
Fast-forward.
快进
Nobody's laughing at you, Michael.
没人在笑你 迈可
You wanted a universal remote control that remote-controls your universe.
你要万能遥控器 遥控万物的遥控器
Yeah, but what controls my dance skills?
是的 哪个钮控制我的舞技？
Oh, Morty likes it too.
莫蒂也喜欢跳
Michael, just hit menu.
迈可 按“菜单”键
On the remote?
遥控器上的？
No, the menu at the Red Lobster. Yes, on the remote.
难道是红龙虾餐厅的菜单吗 当然是遥控上的
Where are we?
我们在哪儿？
Go, Michael, go! One Mississippi. Two Mississippi.
去吧 迈克 去吧！ 一条密西西比河 两条密西西比河
What have I got here? Two, three.
这是啥？ 二 三
Cough syrup's kicking in again.
咳嗽药又起作用了
We have a boy! Is it gonna work?
是个男孩！ 能起作用吗？
What is this?
这是啥？
All right, I love you, Michael. Your life menu.
好的 我爱你 迈克 你的人生菜单
My life has a commentary?
我的人生还有评述？
It's chock-full of goodies.
多着呢
Click it. Click it.
点一下
This is last Tuesday.
这是上星期二
Michael was eagerly awaiting the arrival of his lunch order.
迈克急着等午餐
Who's that, James Earl Jones?
评述人是詹姆斯・琼斯？
James Earl does a lot of voice-over work.
詹姆斯做过很多讲评工作
But his anticipation quickly turned to dismay...
但他的期待很快变成了失望
...as he realized Alice had brought him a cheeseburger...
他点的是汉堡
...instead of a hamburger as he requested.
但爱丽丝买的是芝士汉堡
A cheeseburger? I said a hamburger.
我要的是汉堡 不是芝士汉堡
She always does this to me.
她老是这样
Michael considered demanding that Alice scrape the cheese off...
迈可本想让爱丽丝把芝士抹掉
...but decided not to...
但决定还是不要
...fearing that Alice may spit in...
因为他怕她会往里面吐痰
...or otherwise defile the burger in some manner.
或是别的脏东西进去
A wise decision...
明智的抉择
...for that was exactly what Alice was planning to do.
因为爱丽丝正打算那么做
Are you kidding me? Sneaky.
真的还假的？ 真狡猾
My God.
我的上帝
What else we got here?
还有什么？
"Making of"? Just click.
制作人？ 按吧
Hey, hey, psychedelic. Where are we?
哇 迷幻药啊 我们在哪儿？
Is this a porno or something?
嘿 这是色情片吗？
Oh, Ted. Oh, Teddy!
哦 泰德 哦 泰德
Is that my parents?
这是我爸妈？
They're making you. Like bunny rabbits.
他们在制作你 像兔宝宝一样
That's the spot. Smack my heinie!
就是那里 打我屁股！
Change the channel! How do you do this?
快换台 怎么换呀？
I can't see.
我看不见
What happened? What?
怎么啦？ 啥？
The floor is so mushy and slippery. Feels good on my feet.
这地又湿又滑 我脚还挺舒服的
Check it out. You hit the fast-forward button.
你按到了快进键
I believe we're sometime after your conception.
我们在经历你出生的过程
Okay, very good, Mrs. Newman.
很好 纽曼太太
No! We're in my mother's vagina?
哦不 我们在我妈的阴道里！？
Again. And push.
用力
It's a girl. It's a girl!
是女孩儿 是女孩儿！
Oh, It's a girl. Thank you so much. Thank you for that.
哦 女孩儿 谢谢你 谢谢你
Wait a minute. I'm sorry, it might be a boy.
等等 对不起 可能是男孩
What do you mean, "might be"? What is that?
可能是什么意思？
Maybe that's a penis.
那个可能是小鸡鸡
Maybe that's a pe? That's a penis. That's my penis.
可能是！？ 那就是阴茎 我的小兄弟
Can I see that? Can you bring that a little closer?
我能看看吗？ 再靠近点儿？
See?
看到么？
That's a tiny schmeckel. Yeah?
一根小小的黄瓜 是吗？
We have a boy! We have a boy!
是男孩儿
Your mother must have some superpower eyesight...
你妈一定有超凡的视力
...because I didn't see anything.
因为我什么也看不见
Let's get out of here.
咱们快走吧
So if you think about it...
如果你想想
...I can reexperience any part of my life I want to.
我可以重新体验我一生的任何时刻
It's amazing.
真神奇
What happened? Oh, God, what did I do?
你怎么啦？ 噢 天啊 我做了什么？
Hello? How do I get you back here, pal?
嘿 朋友 我怎么把你弄回来？
Gotcha.
哇！ 骗到你了吧
I'm not freaked out enough?
我还没被吓够呀？
It's simple. Think of a time and a place...
很简单 想好时间地点
...hit rewind, and you're there.
按倒退键 你就在那儿啦
Time and a place. Time and a place.
时间地点 时间地点
Oh, my God. Lake Winnipesaukee.
天啊 温尼波沙克湖
That's me in the Jets shirt.
那是我 穿球衣的
Go, little me, go!
加油啊 小小我 冲啊！
Good hands! Nice hands.
好手 漂亮！
Michael!
迈可！
Michael, dinner's almost ready. Invite your friends if you want to.
迈可 晚餐快好了 你可以请朋友一块儿来吃
So any of you wanna come by my tent for some supper?
你们想来我的帐棚吃晚餐吗？
Or we could eat at my Winnebago and watch Three's Company.
你们也可以来到我家的旅居车 看《三人公司》
Three's Company.
三人公司
That's humiliating.
真丢脸
Mom, why can't we camp in an RV like every other family?
妈 我们为什么不能像别人家 一样开房车来露营呢？
Oh, come on. You call that camping?
得了 那也叫露营？
How can you get close to nature in a tin can like that?
住在那种铁罐里怎么接近大自然？
Plus, it's more fun to have to keep each other warm at night.
再说 晚上挤在一起保暖更有趣呀
Don't you know it.
你不知道吗
No cupcakes yet. But I'm starving.
还没到吃甜点的时候 但是我饿死了
I agree with you, Michael. You know how hungry I am?
我同意 迈可 你知道我多饿吗？
I am so hungry, I could eat this.
我饿得连硬币都能吃
Oh, this is where the quarter trick started.
原来硬币魔术是从这儿开始
How the heck did he do that?
他是怎么变的？
Oh, it's a trick coin you buy at a magic shop.
那是魔术用品店买来的特制硬币
I just couldn't let him know I knew that.
但不能让他知道我已经知道了
That's sweet.
真幸福
Now, I gotta get back to work, so hit play.
我得回去工作了 按播放键
It's a very powerful device. Use it with caution.
这是功能强大的设备 小心使用
Okay.
好的
Who are you?
你是谁？
You know who I am.
你知道的呀
Morty?
莫蒂？
If you have any questions...
如果你有问题…
...call me.
给我打电话
No, Linda, I think Stacy gets the most-beautiful-feet award.
不 琳达 我认为丝黛西的脚 该得到美腿奖
You wanted to see me?
你要见我？
Michael. Look, I'm heading out to the Hamptons in a couple of minutes.
迈可 我马上就要去汉普敦了
I'm counting on you.
一切都靠你了
This hotel project? It's a big fish.
这次的旅馆计划 是条大鱼
You reel it in for me and it's "Howdy, partner."
你把它给我钓上来 那咱们就是 您好 伙伴儿
Okay. Thank you.
好的 谢谢
Screw it up, though, and it's "Back to the mailroom, atrium boy."
搞砸了 你就去中亭发邮件吧
Mr. Ammer, Denise just called.
安莫先生 丹尼斯打电话
She's gotta go to rehab again, so she can't make it to the Hamptons.
她又得去修复不能跟你去汉普敦
I'm gonna be alone on the Fourth of July?
国庆假日 我一个人过？
Mr. Ammer, if you need female companionship this weekend...
安莫先生 如果周末你需要女伴
...my wife's friend Janine, wow.
我太太的朋友洁宁…
Really? What's she like?
真的？ 她长得怎样？
Let's just say she will eat you up, sir.
我只能说 她能生吞了你
Excuse me. I'm sorry to interrupt...
对不起 打扰
...but this is kind of important. Okay.
这很重要
Go to the bathroom. Okay.
自己去厕所 好的
Dude! You suck so bad.
你真笨！
Do not. Hey, Dad.
我才不是 嗨 老爸
How you doing, buddy? Playing some catch?
嗨 儿子 玩接球吗？
Actually, we're playing some drop, because Ben hasn't caught one yet.
其实是玩掉球 本到现在一个球都没接住
Darn it.
该死
You're a regular Derek Jeter yourself, O'Doyle.
小子 我看你也不怎样嘛
Love you, kid. Love you too, Dad.
我爱你 儿子 我也爱你 老爸
Mommy!
妈咪
No, I know. Well, I thought she should've gotten voted off.
不 我知道 我觉得她不该投票
But did you see her Kate Spade handbag? It was gorgeous.
但你看到了她的凯特 手袋了吗？ 漂亮极了
Wait, hold on a second, Trudy. I gotta say hi to your son.
等等 别挂 楚蒂 我得跟你儿子问声好
I told your parents to come for dinner. Really? That sounds good.
我邀请你爸妈过来吃晚饭 真的？ 好主意
It'd be fun for them to be here for the sleepover.
他们来陪孩子们过夜一定很好玩
Okay, so great. Yeah.
好 再见 拜拜
We'll see you guys later. Okay, bye-bye.
到时候见，拜拜
It's not gonna kill you to eat dinner with your family, sweetie.
和你家人吃个饭不会要你的命
I know, I just gotta build an entire model tonight.
我知道 但我今晚得把模型弄好
I'm the leader! No, I'm the leader!
我是头 不 我是头！
Go say hi to Daddy. Go on.
去跟爸爸问好 快去
I can't take a whole night of this.
要是整晚都这样 我可受不了
And I'm not going to. Q, R, S, T, U...
我也不想受 Q R S T U…
Cool.
酷
I can skip chapters.
我能跳过这段
What a family.
真是个好家庭
All right, let's get dinner over with. Next.
好啦 快把晚餐吃完 下一段
Next.
下一段
Everyone's done but you, buddy. Let's go.
只剩你一个还没吃完 老兄
Will you stop already?
你完了？
Oh, boy, Dad's quarter trick. I can't wait not to see it.
要命 老爸的硬币魔术 我等不及了看了
Alone in my basement at last.
独自在地下室
Should I do my work and become partner now? I think so.
该努力工作成为老板的合伙人了
Let's get to it.
开工
Michael? Yo.
迈可？ 恩
We don't wanna interrupt.
我们不想再打扰你
We're taking off. Thanks for a great night.
我们走了 谢谢盛情款待
You had a fun time hanging out with me?
你们和我玩很开心？
That was... We did good, right?
恩 我们玩的很高兴
Good night, honey. Love you.
再见 亲爱的 爱你们
My schmeckel got bigger now that I'm older, just so you guys know that.
我的小黄瓜随着年龄也长大了
It couldn't have gotten any smaller.
反正不可能长的比以前更小
Yeah, yeah.
哦 是
It looked like a little Tic Tac.
以前像个小不点口香糖
Yeah, come here, I'll freshen your breath.
嗯 过来 让我替你除口臭
Bye, you guys. Bye, sweetie.
再见 再见 宝贝
Good night, sweetie.
晚安 甜心
Great dinner, honey.
晚餐真棒 老婆
See? Was that so bad?
真的 很糟糕吗？
Kidding me? I had fun.
你说笑吧 我高兴得很
Good for you. Can you watch the gang for 10 minutes while I clean up?
那就好 帮我看孩子十分钟 我得洗东西
Can't you? I just... I got so much stuff to do here.
自己看吧 我很忙
Oh, you got stuff to do?
哦 你忙！？
I got ghost stories, charades, the dishes...
我又讲鬼故事 猜字谜 还要洗碗
...and then I gotta sew the duck's head back on for Sundance...
现在还得替狗把鸭子的头缝上
...and fix his butthole.
还要把屁眼儿给补起来
Way to go, champ.
干得好 冠军
I wish I had time to do all that stuff.
我希望我有时间能做那么多事呢
Give me a break, Michael.
饶了我吧 迈可
You're a big boy. You set your own priorities.
你是大人了 做事得有先后
I'm asking for 10 minutes, not for, like, a whole day.
我只要你十分钟 又不是一整天
You don't have to do that much.
你也没有那么多
How big a deal is that? I am so tired of having this argument.
有什么大不了得？ 我烦透了吵架
I skipped the whole fight.
我跳过了整场吵架
Babe?
宝贝？
I can't sleep. You can't?
我睡不着 怎么啦？
I feel bad that we keep arguing.
咱们老是吵架 我很难过
I know. Don't be upset, okay?
我知道 别难过 好吗？
I was a jerk. You are a jerk.
是我不好 嗯 你坏蛋
I love you. I love you too.
我爱你 我也爱你
Yes. That smells good. What?
你好香 什么？
Michael. Stop it. The sleepover will catch us.
喂 迈可 别 他们会听到
They ain't gonna hear us. Come on.
他们听不到 来吧
Okay. Quietly try and coax me into it.
好吧 轻点声 慢慢让我进入状态
I gotta get back to work. Can't we just do it?
不 难道我们不能只是做吗？
No, we can't just do it. Honey, come on.
不 我们不能这么快 亲爱的 来吧
I mean, I don't have any new moves for you. It's the same stuff.
我没有新招了 都是那一套
Just think of last time and use that.
你就把上次的拿来算这次的
I like the old moves. Come on.
我喜欢老套得 来吧
All right.
好吧
This time you be Sundance, I'll be the duck.
这次你当狗狗 我当鸭鸭
Yeah? But you gotta massage me first.
好啊 你得先爱抚我才成
Great, I love giving massages.
好啊 我最喜欢爱抚你
Massaging away here.
别摸这里
Oh, that feels good. Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
嗯 好舒服 哦也
We did it? Well, you did.
我们做了吗？ 是只有你做了吧
I didn't want the whole thing to go that fast.
我可不想要整个过程都这么快
I don't think anybody did.
谁都不会想
Yeah. I'll get you next time.
哦 下次补偿你
Thanks.
好吧
So we good for tomorrow?
明天没问题吧？
What are you talking about?
明天什么？
At dinner.
吃饭的时候
You said we'd go to lunch tomorrow and pick out your dad's birthday gift.
你说明天去我们去吃午餐 给你爸买生日礼物
Dad's gift is...
爸的礼物…
Of course. I said so, so I'll be there. Okay.
既然说了 我会去的 好的
Need another massage or anything? Oh, go away.
还要按摩或什么吗？ 不要 你走吧
I gotta go work.
好啦 我去做事了
Hey, Morty. It's Michael Newman.
喂 莫蒂 我是迈可・纽曼
Yeah, can I talk to you for a minute?
我能和你谈谈吗？
Hang on for a second, someone's at my door.
等一下 有人敲我的门
Hello, Michael. Where'd you come from?
迈可 你从哪儿蹦出来的？
You don't wanna know.
你最好不要知道
Can we take a walk? Sure.
出去走走吗？ 当然
It's simple. You must have been on autopilot.
原因很简单 你一定设成自动导航了
Autopilot?
自动导航？
That's what happens to you when you fast-forward.
你按了快进 就会这样
Okay. Yeah. I'll show you.
好的 我示范给你看
Here.
这里
See? That's you on autopilot.
瞧 那是你在自动导航模式
The lights are on but nobody's home.
灯开着 却没人在家
The remote lets your mind skip around...
摇控器让你的思想跳过了…
...but your body actually stays put for the boring stuff.
但身体还得过那些无聊的时间
We should go to lunch tomorrow and pick out your dad's birthday gift.
老公 明天我们吃午餐去给你爸买礼物
Sounds good.
好主意
So she did tell me.
她果然跟我说过
I'm having conversations on autopilot, then.
我在自动导航模式下和人说话
You're not gonna be the life of the party, but yes.
你说是自动导航 也没错
Everyone goes on autopilot now and then.
所有人都时不时会自动导航
The big difference is now you've got a nifty remote...
最大的差别是 你有了万能遥控器
...to help you decide when.
帮你觉得是什么时候
This thing is the best.
这玩意儿太棒了
By the way, your wife? Absolutely gorgeous.
顺便说一句 你太太真美
She is, isn't she? Perfect face. Tight, rocking body.
她的确很美 对吧？ 完美的容貌 身上没赘肉
You okay?
你没事吧？
Amazing. What is?
真令人惊讶 什么事？
She fell for a schlub like you.
鲜花插在牛粪上
I'm a schlub?
我是牛粪？
I don't know about that, pal. I see a good-Iooking man right there.
难说吧 那家伙很英俊呀
You wanna see what a stud I used to be? Yeah?
你想看他以前的样子吗？
All right, let's take a look at some of the girls...
那好 让你瞧瞧他以前的女朋友
...I used to fool around with before I met Donna.
我认识唐娜前 和什么样的女孩子们约会
Is that a man or a woman?
男的女的啊？
It's a woman.
女人
What is this, Animal Planet?
这！？ 《动物星球》吗？
Stop. Yes.
算了吧 嗯
Sometimes it's better to keep certain memories just in your head.
有些事还是留在记忆深处较好
So I've learned, Morty.
我又学到了 莫蒂
Good night. Thank you.
晚安 谢谢你
Good night, Michael.
晚安 迈可
I'm getting sick, man. Fast-forward me till I'm better.
我好像病了 快进到我好点的时候
Michael, honey, wake up. You'll be late for work.
迈可 起床 上班要迟到了
What? It's Monday already?
怎么？ 已经星期一了？
Are you kidding me? No more phlegm?
真的么？ 没有痰了？
I skipped an entire cold?
整个感冒都跳过了？
Thanks to you, baby! I love you!
感谢你 宝贝 我爱你
No more Tylenol!
再也不用感冒药了
I don't remember doing any work this weekend.
我不记得这周做了什么了
But apparently I did.
显然我已经做好了
Bad news. There's no hot water. What? I gotta take a shower.
坏消息 没热水了 什么？ 我得洗个澡
Well, you're gonna freeze your bun-buns off.
你的屁股得挨冻了
It's all good.
没关系
Yes! Look at me.
瞧瞧我
All showered and dressed and looking sexy.
洗好澡 穿好衣服 性感极了
I like that. I...
我喜欢这样 我…
Did you smoke crack, Daddy?
爹地 你抽大麻了吗？
Just watch your toons and have a great day with Mommy today, okay?
看你的卡通 和妈妈乖乖在家 好吗？
Eating cupcakes like your old man. Right here, baby.
你吃甜点就像你老爸 再见宝贝
Dad? Yes, sir?
爸 什么事？
Are you gonna have to work late again tonight?
你今天又要加班吗？
Unfortunately, yes. Is there anything we can do to help?
很不幸 是的 我们帮什么忙吗？
Well, I'm gonna be partner soon, and I'm gonna need new building designs.
我快成了公司合伙人了 我需要很多新的建筑设计点子
So if you guys have any cool ideas, draw them up for me.
如果你们有什么好点子 画给我吧
Okay. Rock 'n' roll.
好 摇滚
I get the paper. I got the crayons.
我有纸 我有蜡笔
Would you stop talking and fix the sewer?
别聊了 快把下水道修修
You're on it now, yeah. Yeah.
大家都在 是的 是的
Traffic, traffic, no more traffic.
堵车 堵车 没有堵车
Wait a sec!
等等！
Here we go! Mama!
冲啊 妈妈！
Yeah! That's what I'm talking about, baby!
这才像话 我的宝贝
You look a little pale there, pal. Let me fix that.
老兄 你怎么脸色苍白 我替你补救一下
Oh, look at you now. You're all yellow from the scurvy.
瞧你脸色泛黄 一定是坏血病
Captain.
船长
Don't get the Hulk angry. You won't like him when he's angry.
别惹绿巨人 他生气你就完蛋了
Oh, there's Barney.
紫恐龙巴尼来了
I love you, you love me
我爱你们 你们爱我
That jogger had giant boobies
慢跑女郎有对大胸部
Okay. Let's get you that tan you been searching for.
来点你想要的日晒肤色
That's it. That's it.
对了 对了
Check out Julio Iglesias... Pretty.
胡利欧・伊格西斯… 棒极了
Looking good, Mr. Newman. Really? Thank you very much, Judy.
真精神 纽曼先生 真的？ 谢谢你茱蒂
Finish? Did I finish? I believe I finished.
完成了吗？ 我完成了吗？ 我想我完成了
Let's see here. Look at that. Very impressive, Michael.
我们来看看 印象深刻 迈可
Yeah, the river in the lobby. This is actually pretty good, man.
是的 大厅的河流 真不错
Where did you find the time to get a tan?
你还有时间去日光浴？
I guess I can do it all, sir. You can do it all.
我想我是全能 你是全能的
All right, all right, everybody. It's sexual-harassment-speech day.
好啦 大家注意 今天是性骚扰讲座
Now, anyone can be a victim of sexual harassment:
每个人都可能成为性骚扰的受害者
Blue collar, white collar, a woman, a man.
蓝领 白领 女人 男人
Even the office slut.
即使是办公室的荡妇也不例外
Not that I'm mentioning any names...
我还是别说出名字来
...Stacy.
史黛西
Here we go. Sexual harassment can come in many forms.
性骚扰有很多种形式
You see, what is hilarious to some, could be offensive to others.
有些行为某人喜欢 却冒犯了其他人
Let me try to give you a real-life example because I'm sure I've done it.
让我给个实际的例子 我以前也做过
Like the day I said, "You want a promotion, break out the lotion."
有次我对某人说 想要升职 就拿润滑液来吧
I was technically engaged in sexual harassment.
我技术上犯了语言性骚扰
Hilarious sexual harassment, if you ask me.
如果你问我 这玩意儿好笑极了
Now, there is also homosexual harassment.
同时还有同性之间的性骚扰
Now, this is like when one dude comes up to another...
比方男人向男人说些
...and says something cheeky. This will be good.
暧昧的话
Proceed.
继续
I don't know about you Americans...
我不懂你们美国人
...but to me there is no doubt...
但对我来说 毫无疑问
...Ichiro is the greatest of all time.
一郎一直都是最伟大的
Yeah, he's incredible.
是的 他棒极了
You gotta admit, you can always count on Matsui.
你得承认 松井最值得信赖
Oh, Matsui.
哦 松井
Well, if you guys love Ichiro and Matsui so much, let's order them both.
如果大家都喜欢一郎和松井 那就两道菜都点吧
I'll eat anything.
我什么都能吃
Excuse us for a moment. Absolutely, Mr. Watsuhita.
失陪一下 没问题 和津先生
See you guys in a bit.
待会儿见
Ichiro and Matsui are baseball players. You just insulted their national heroes.
一郎和松井是棒球明星 你刚才污辱了他们的民族英雄
I'm going to the bathroom to slit my wrists.
我去厕所了
I'll be here.
我在这儿
These morons are so boring.
这种蠢蛋太无聊了
They make me wanna chop my own dick off.
他们让我想割下我的弟弟
That hotel design? I'd like to rip it up.
那旅馆设计图？ 我真想撕了
Egghead watched a bad documentary on Asian architecture.
那自以为聪明的家伙看了部 糟糕的亚洲建筑记录片
Who needs a stupid river in the lobby?
谁会在大厅修人工小溪？
Let's build more rooms and maximize profits.
应该多修房间 最大化利润
Eat as fast as you can.
大家尽快吃完
Then we can get out of here...
然后离开这里
...and do Jell-O shots at America's greatest cultural achievement:
再赶去美国最大的文化成就
T.G.I. Friday's.
TGI星期五餐厅
T.G.I. Friday's!
TGI星期五！
All right, Michael, save us. I'm all over it, baby.
好了 迈可 全靠你了 我会的
Before we order, I was looking at our proposal. You know what?
点菜之前 我重新看了一遍设计图
After getting to know you a little bit, I realize this is not what you're about.
在对大家有所了解之后 我意识到这设计并不适合你们
In fact, let's just throw it out, all right? Start from scratch.
实际上 这东西还是扔了算了
The river in the lobby idea, what an egghead move.
大厅里的小溪 多愚蠢的主意啊
Let's just keep the plans simple, forget all the niceties, maximize our revenue.
我们简单点 去掉无用的景观 利润最大化更重要
That's what it's all about anyways, the profits.
不管怎样 利润才是关键
But do me a favor. Just give us your account and your trust.
但是你们得给我们投资和信任
That way we can get the hell out of this dump, go to T.G.I. Friday's...
大家都可以快点离开这里 去TGI星期五
...do some Jell-O shots till this guy pukes up a lung.
去玩玩吉露果子冻射击 直到那家伙呕吐为止
Fuck, yeah.
真他妈的棒
That's what I'm talking about.
这才是我说的！
Yes, yes!
好极了
The king is home! Hello, hello!
皇帝回宫了！你们好
How can you goons sleep when you know I got you presents?
我有礼物给你们 你们还睡得着？
You did? What is it?
真的么？ 是什么？
What is it? Well, if you bring your tushies downstairs, we'll find out.
是什么 下来看看就知道了
I'm coming. I'm coming.
我来了 我来了
Honey, get your sweet little buns downstairs too. Come on, come on!
甜心 带着你的小屁股 快下楼来看看 快 快！
Come and get them.
来拿礼物
Awesome! No way! Yeah, yeah.
不是吧 太棒了！ 是啊 是啊
It must have cost a million dollars! That's chump change now.
肯定要一百万元吧？ 小意思啦
You guys deserve the best...
你们应得最好的
...and that's what you're gonna get from now on, okay?
从现在起 你们要享受最好的 好吗？
What's all this?
都怎么了？
Look who's here. You guys wanna ride these bikes?
看看谁在这 你们想骑骑吗？
Yeah! Let's take them outside!
想！ 骑出去吧！
Wake the O'Doyles, let them see what you got.
弄醒欧多雷 给那小子瞧瞧
These are the coolest bikes in the whole town.
这是全镇最酷的自行车
Kevin O'Doyle's gonna shit himself.
凯文・欧多雷定会无地自容
Don't think I forgot my beautiful wife. Oh, my gosh.
别以为我忘了我美丽的老婆 哦 我的天那
It's not a bike or a cowboy hat, but you're gonna like this, I hope.
不是单车或牛仔帽 但我希望你会喜欢的
Oh, Michael, it's beautiful. I heard you talking to my mother.
哇 迈可 真漂亮 我偷听到你跟我妈说话了
I love it! You look good, baby.
我好喜欢 配你真好看 宝贝
I got myself a celebratory cigar too. Why not?
我也为自己买了庆祝雪茄 为什么不呢？
What are we celebrating?
我们要庆祝什么？
"What are we celebrating?" We're healthy, we got a great family...
庆祝什么？ 我们都很健康 我们是个美好的家庭
...I'm Ammer's newest partner...
我是老板新入股的合伙人
Oh, my God, you're kidding! Honey, congratulations!
哦 天哪 不是开玩笑吧？ 宝贝 祝贺你！
I knew it! I knew you'd be psyched! I love it! I love you!
我就知道你会很兴奋 我喜欢 我爱你
I single-handedly landed the Watsuhita account.
我单枪匹马搞定了日本人的生意
That's incredible. I knew it was gonna be a great day.
那真太棒了 我知道今天会是个好日子
I heard our song on the radio. We have a song?
我在广播里听到我们的歌了 我们有歌吗？
Honey. The song that was playing during our first kiss.
甜心 我们初吻时的歌
Come on. You're kidding me, right?
拜托 你是不是又在逗我 是吗？
I know our song. Our song. Of course I know our song. Our song is...
我知道那首歌 我们的歌 当然知道 是…
What the hell was that song?
是他妈的什么歌？
I remember this place.
我记得这地方 还有
And... Oh, my God.
天哪
Wolverine's goofy cousin.
金刚狼的痴呆表亲
But look at you. Wow. You are out of his league, aren't you?
看看你 你不在他的联盟 对吗？
Oh, yeah, the notes.
对了 纸条
Smooth, buddy.
真有你的 老兄
Oh, look at her.
哦 看看她
What's gonna happen? You got an answer to that?
你应该如何回应才好呢
Okay. Seal the deal, pal.
搞定它 老兄
All she's thinking about is, "I am not kissing that beard.
她一定在想 不要亲那大胡子
Absolutely not, that's gonna hurt me."
绝对不要 肯定很疼
Wait a minute.
等一下
Yeah, Newman. Get it.
是的 纽曼
Yeah.
对了
Donna!
唐娜！
Donna. Oh, my God.
唐娜 哦 我的天啊
I'm so horny now.
哦 我的上帝 我要发骚了
Oh, God, I'm not. Get me out of here.
够了 该回去了
"Linger" by The Cranberries was playing during our first juicy kiss.
“酸莓合唱团”的“逗留” 就是我们初吻时的歌
And, my God, you looked beautiful in that pink sweater you were wearing.
天哪 你穿那件粉色的衣服太美了
Honey, you remember what I was wearing?
哦 亲爱的你还记得我穿什么
Of course. I remember what Janine was wearing.
当然 我还记得洁宁的打扮
She scared the shit out of me then.
她把我吓惨了
I love you.
我爱你
I love you too, honey.
我也爱你 宝贝
Hi, Mr. Newman.
你好 纽曼先生
Right this way, Michael.
这边走 迈可
Hey, my new star. Congratulations. Sit down, big guy.
嘿 我的新星 祝贺你 坐吧 伙计
All right.
好的
I am a little tired.
我有点儿累
The family was up late last night celebrating.
我家昨天庆祝到很晚
You really knocked one out of the park last night, didn't you?
你昨天的表现好的出乎意料
Hey, you were great too.
嘿 你也很好
All you gotta do is draw up the construction plans.
现在你只要完成结构设计图
If Watsuhita commits to the bulk of the funds...
如果他们交了钱…
...I'm looking at my new partner.
我在找我的新合伙人
I thought I was already your partner.
我以为我已经是你的合伙人了
Whoa, cowboy.
喔 牛仔
I said, "Land the Watsuhita account, you'll get promoted."
我说做成日本人交易 你就会升职
I didn't mean right this second. But I already told my wife, sir.
我没有说立即 但是我已经告诉我的妻子了
I spent money I don't have.
我花了我没赚到的钱
To do these documents is gonna take me months.
交那些贷款要用我几个月的工资
Then you better get started.
那么你最好开始工作了
Wow, I just got a big headache!
哦 我的头怎么这么疼
Was I hit by a train or something? I didn't see anything.
我被火车还是什么撞了吗 我什么都没看见
I forgot to tell you. I hung out with your friend Janine this weekend.
忘了告诉你 我这个周末约了你的朋友洁宁
I hope she's doing your brother right now, you big-headed buffoon.
我希望她正和搞你哥哥 你这个自大的小丑
No, no, no. You got more.
不不不 再多给你点
Yeah.
好耶
Anyway, the sooner you get back to work...
不管怎样 你越快回来工作
...the sooner you'll be partnerized.
就越快升到合伙人
I taste shit. You do?
我感觉到大便的味道 是吗
Stacy! Did you put shit in my lunch?
史黛西 你在我的午饭里放了大便吗
I'm gonna get going now, sir.
我要走了 先生
Stacy!
史黛西
Have you considered the consequences...
你考虑过你现在想做的事情
...of the thing you're thinking about doing?
和他的结果吗
Yeah. What are you saying, I shouldn't do it?
嗯 你在说什么 我应该这样做
It's your life. What you do with the remote is your decision, Michael.
那是你的人生 你拿那个遥控器 做什么是你的决定 迈可
I know, so, I mean, we're talking a couple of months here.
我知道 所以 我的意思是 我们在这里说了几个月的话
I fast-forward through it, what am I gonna miss?
我用遥控器快进 我错过了什么？
Thirty arguments and a haircut?
吵架30次 理发一次
Remember the leprechaun?
记得那个妖精吗？
The one from the cereal ad.
那个谷类食品广告里的
"They're magically delicious." That guy?
“它们好吃的神奇” 那个人？
He's always chasing the pot of gold at the end of the rainbow.
他总是在彩虹的尽头雕刻金罐子
But when he gets there at the end of the day...
但是当他在一天结束到那里的时候
...it's just corn flakes.
只是玉米片罢了
Michael. Yes.
迈可 嗯
You don't understand the metaphor? I won't do it, all right.
你不明白里面的隐喻的？ 我明白不了 好吧
Dad? Yeah.
爸爸 什么事
We have some designs for you. It's not a good time, man.
我们有一些设计给你看 现在可不是好时间
Maybe they'll help you finish quicker.
它们可能可以帮你快点完成
All right. You want me to look at it? Let me see.
好的 你想让我看这个？ 那让我看看吧
The ceiling's too high, the hallway's too narrow...
天花板太高 走廊太窄
...stairway placement makes no sense at all.
楼梯放在这根本没有用
What the hell's this room made of? Pizza.
这该死的房子要用什么材料建呢 匹萨
Well, it's stupid. Next. What is yours made of?
好的 这个想法真是白痴 你的要用什么材料
Pickles. Oh, don't be a baby.
泡菜 哦 不要那么幼稚
Michael, have you lost your mind? He's 7 years old.
迈可 你失去理智了吗？ 他只有7岁
If he wants a playroom made of pizza, then why not?
如果他认为游戏房是匹萨做的 为什么不行呢？
Maybe he's gotta grow up sometime and get the hell off Fantasy Island.
也许什么时候他长大了 会到什么该死的梦幻岛
Hey, pizza boy. Life ain't about being creative.
嘿 匹萨男孩 生活不是凭空创造出来的
It's about kissing ass, playing it safe, making your boss a lot of money...
是拍马匹 小心操作 给你老板赚很多钱
...in hopes one day he might throw you a stinking bone. All right?
希望他有一天可以 丢给你一根烂骨头 知道吗？
Yes, sir.
是的 先生
Ammer didn't make you partner, did he?
安莫没把你选为合伙人 对不对
Oh, honey, I'm so sorry.
哦 宝贝 我很抱歉
But we'll get through this, okay? I promise.
但是你可以熬过去的 对吗？ 我保证
Jeez! Man, that's all we ever do is get through it.
嘿 伙计 现在我们所能做的一切 只是“熬过去”
When is it gonna end?
什么时候才是个头？
Pretty sweet, eh?
很可爱 嗯？
Two queen beds, full kitchen, steam shower...
两张大床 整体厨房 蒸气浴室
...and satellite TV with surround sound.
还有带环绕立体声的卫星电视
Why are you always trying to hurt me? One day I'm gonna hurt you back.
你为什么老是想伤害我？ 有一天我会报仇的
Michael Newman, I didn't know you smoked cigars.
迈可・纽曼 我不知道你还抽雪茄
And now's the time.
现在是时候了
No, Kathy, this isn't mine.
不 凯西 这不是我的
I took it out of Kevin's hands. Yeah, he was smoking like a chimney.
我从凯文手里拿来的 他像个烟囱一样抽雪茄
No, I wasn't!
不 我没有
I think I smell marijuana in it.
我觉得我在里面闻到大麻的味道
Kevin O'Doyle, you get your ass in this house right now!
凯文・欧多雷 快点给我进来 马上
I hate you.
我恨你
Are you deaf? Move it! I don't wanna have to ask you again!
你聋了吗？ 还不快跑 我不想再叫你第二次
Dope is for dopes, buddy!
毒品是给笨蛋玩的
Get your ass in this house!
快点给我进屋
We don't have any other choice, guys.
我没有其他选择了 伙计们
No fair! I don't wanna return my bike! We have to, honey.
这不公平 我不想退掉我的自行车 我们不得不这样 宝贝
But Daddy gave them to us! Because he loves you.
但是这是爸爸送给我们的 因为他爱你们
Unfortunately, there was a mix-up at Daddy's work.
很不幸的是 爸爸的工作有点问题
We need to bring the bikes back for now.
我们需要现在就退了自行车
But I already told Kevin O'Doyle I got a new bike.
但是我已经告诉凯文・欧多雷 我有自行车了
Well, we can paint my old bike and make it look new.
那么 我们可以把以前的车重刷漆 让它看起来和新的一样
That's a girl's bike. All the kids will make fun of me.
那是女孩的车 所有的孩子都会嘲笑我的
No!
不
I wanna keep my bike!
我想把我的自行车留下
I can't take this anymore.
我不能再这样下去了
Fast-forward me to my promotion.
让我快进到我升职的时候
So here's to Michael Newman...
迈可・纽曼
...the greatest partner I could ever dream of.
我梦寐以求的合伙人
Hear, hear!
听 听
Thank you. Thank you, guys. My family thanks you.
谢谢 谢谢 伙计们 我的家人谢谢你们
I'm gonna do the best I can and I won't let you down, I promise.
我会做到最好不会然让你失望的 我保证
Yeah!
耶
Congratulations, Mr. Newman. This is great. Thank you.
祝贺你 纽曼先生 这太好了 谢谢你
How's it feel, killer?
感觉怎么样？
Feels incredible, sir. Well, you earned it. I'm telling you.
我觉得难以置信 先生 你做到了 我现在告诉你
Not just because of that Watsuhita project either.
不仅仅是因为 和津的那个企划案
For helping me pick up the slack now I'm spending time with my lady.
帮我抽出空闲 现在我有更多时间 陪我的女士了
Hey, Dinkie.
嘿 小家伙
Are you kidding me? You guys have been dating a couple months now?
你在开玩笑吗？ 你们已经约会几个月了？
That's pretty huge for this one.
这真是很难啊
No, the first few months were easy.
不 前几个月挺好的
It was the one-year hump that was the tough part.
一年的时候挺难熬的
Her inappropriate weekend with my brother in Cabo...
她 在一个不幸的周末和我弟弟卡伯
...well, that was a potential speed bump.
对我们打击很大
But, well, Dr. Bergman helped us work through it, didn't he, honey?
但是 博格曼医生帮我们度过难关 对不对啊 宝贝？
How's he doing for you and Donna?
他是怎么处理你和唐娜的事情的？
Dr. Bergman. What do you mean?
博格曼医生 你是什么意思？
Oh, you know what, sweetie? It's none of our business.
哦 你知道什么 宝贝 那不关我们的事
Let's let Michael bask in his glory. Cheers.
我们让迈可为自己高兴吧 干杯
Bask away, partner.
高兴吧 合伙人
Took that bastard a year to promote me?
和那个人在一起一年才让我升职？
What else did I miss?
我还错过了什么？
Shit. Need something, Mr. Newman?
天啊 需要什么吗 纽曼先生
Who are you? Kirsten, your assistant.
你是谁？ 柯尔斯顿 你的助理
What happened to Alice?
爱丽丝怎么了？
She moved to Accounting. Couldn't handle your hours.
她去了会计部 做你助手太累了
And she prefers to be called Alan now. Remember?
还有她现在喜欢别人叫她艾伦 记住了吗？
No.
不
No! And who the hell's Dr. Bergman?
不 那谁是该死的博格曼医生？
And I feel like Michael's making no effort to connect with me at all.
我觉得我和迈可交流他没有反应
No, no. I want to. I want to. It's... I'm on autopilot.
不 不 我想 那是因为我在自动模式下
"I'm on autopilot." More like auto-zombie.
“我在自动模式下” 行尸走肉还差不多
Good one, Donna.
说的好 唐娜
"Good one, Donna"? Michael, relax.
“说的好 唐娜”？ 迈可 放轻松
Who is this bigmouth? Why can't you and I just talk?
这个长舌妇是谁？ 为什么我们不能单独谈谈？
Why? Because there is no talking to you. You're never home to talk to.
为什么不？ 因为你不和我说话 你在家里根本就不说话
And when you are, you're just sitting there staring off into space.
当你在家里的时候 你只是坐着盯着一个地方发呆
What do you want from me?
你想要我怎么样
This is what happens. He's gonna answer his phone.
就是这样 他就去接电话了
What the heck happened? I didn't even touch the remote.
怎么回事？ 我甚至没有碰遥控器
Great, you gonna start watching TV at dinner?
好的 你们要在晚饭的时候看电视吗？
Oh, can we?
哦 可以吗？
Samantha. My little angel. Look at you.
萨曼塔 我的小天使 看看你
Look how long your hair's getting.
看看你头发都长这么长了
When did you grow up? Ben, get over here.
你什么时候长大的？ 本 过来这里
Don't worry. I'm not gonna work tonight.
别担心 我今晚不工作了
Watch Dragon Tales together. What do you say?
一起看龙的传说 你说什么？
Dragon Tales is for babies, Dad. I wanna watch CSI.
龙的传说是给小孩看的 我要看CSI
Yeah, CSI.
对 CSI(犯罪现场调查)
It's the episode when they find the lady's arm.
这是找到女人胳膊的那一集
What happened? I missed the whole Dragon Tales era?
怎么回事？ 我错过了整个龙的传说的时期？
Whoa, hey, hello.
哦 嘿 你好
What are you doing? Come here! Give me my Twinkie!
你在做什么？ 过来 把我的夹心饼干还给我！
Get back here, you freaking gremlin!
过来 你这个反常的小鬼！
Don't yell at Peanut because he found your Twinkie stash.
不要因为花生咬着你的夹心饼干 就对它大叫
Who's Peanut? Where's Sundance?
谁是花生？ 阳阳去哪儿了？
Don't mention Sundance. The kids just stopped crying.
别提阳阳 孩子们才刚不为这个哭
About what? Why? What happened?
为了什么？ 为什么？ 发生了什么？
He died?
他死了？
Oh, no, no, no. Oh, no.
哦 不 不 不 不 不
The stupid idiot and soft fur.
那个傻孩子还有柔软的毛啊
Daddy held it in so long. He was the best dog!
爸爸在意太久了 他是最好的狗！
He's finally letting himself feel it.
他自己最后才意识到
One night when the duck's head was off...
那天晚上鸭子的头掉了
...he tried to hump my leg and I didn't let him...
他想爬在我腿上 我没允许
...and I should've and I'm sorry.
我应该让他爬的 我对不起他啊
What an idiot. It's okay, it's okay.
多傻啊 好了 没事了
What the heck did I do?
我都做了什么啊？
I love you. Do you still love me?
我爱你 你还爱我吗？
Oh, Michael.
哦 迈可
It's been...
这
I'm really confused.
我真的很困扰
No, no, no. I'll change, okay? I'll be a better man, I promise.
不 不 我会改的 好吗？ 我会变成更好的人 我保证
Don't go, don't go. I'll stop working so much, okay?
不要走 不要走 我不再工作那么多了？
I'll be with you. Just stay with me.
我要和你在一起 只和我在一起好吗？
Oh, my God, it didn't take the duck long to get over Sundance.
天啊 鸭子这么快就忘记阳阳了
It's a little deviant, but it's kind of turning me on.
也许有点太不正常 但这让我觉得很性奋
Yeah, well, let's kiss and make up.
是吗 那我们也来一下
No. No!
不 不
It's not my fault.
这不是我的错
It jumped on its own. I didn't even hit the button.
它自己跳的 我甚至没有按按钮
Not even close.
一点感觉都没有
Yes?
什么？
You scared... Honey, what's going on down there?
你害怕 宝贝 楼下怎么回事？
It's all right! I... There was a mouse! I killed it!
没什么 有一只老鼠 我把它杀了
It's dead! But it broke the table first!
它死了 不过桌子被弄坏了
How did you get in here? I had a feeling you wanted to see me.
你怎么来的 我的直觉告诉我你想见我
I'm freaking out. This thing, it's broken.
很反常 这个东西 坏了
It's just... It's fast-forwarding on its own now.
那只是 它自己会自动快进
It's not a malfunction, it's a feature.
那不是故障 而是特色
It's using its memory to execute your preferences.
它会用记忆来执行你的偏好
It remembers stuff? What do you mean?
它会记东西？ 什么意思？
It's an advanced piece of equipment, like TiVo.
这是这个东西的高级部分 就像TiVo(智能电视)
You could call it MeVo.
你可以叫它MeVo
I fast-forwarded through sex one time, I don't wanna skip it forever.
我一次快进了做爱 我不想永远都这样
I like sex. It feels good.
我喜欢做爱 那感觉很好
Correct me if I'm wrong, but you fast-forwarded through an entire year.
如果我错了可以纠正我 但是你快进了一整年
That's a lot of sex.
那要做很多次爱
Put it all together, that's like 30 minutes' worth for you.
把它们都放在一起 对你来说才不过30分钟
Oh, no, no. So what, everything I fast-forwarded...
哦 不 不 那么 所有我快进的东西
...it's gonna do it on its own now? Pretty much.
它们都会自动进行？ 没错
No more showering, no more traffic.
再也不用洗澡 再没有交通
No more arguing. No more sickness.
再没有争吵 再没有病痛
This is bad, this is bad.
这太糟了 这太糟了
You take it back, I'm deactivating my service.
你把这个拿回去吧 我不要这个了
I quit, I quit. Thanks for everything, all right, but I...
我放弃 我放弃 谢谢你 但是我
Yeah.
好的
You... This is not...
你 这个不
Don't be mean.
不要这样
Nice hat.
帽子挺好看的
No, no, no.
不 不 不
Get away from me. Just get away. Get away. Leave me alone.
离开我 离开我 滚 不要理我
Is this a stickup? Or are you just happy?
那里是不是突起？ 或者你太高兴了？
Yeah? I'm gonna take my clothes off, then...
啊？ 我把衣服都脱了 然后
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
如果我是你就不会那么做
There's only one place left for it to pop up.
你会突然出现的地方只有一个了
Oh. No, no, I don't want that. Come on, man.
哦 不不 我不想这样 来吧 伙计
I told you, this item is nonreturnable.
我告诉过你 这个是不退换的
Come on, just take it. Until we meet again.
来吧 你就拿着吧 直到我们再遇到
Don't do that. Come on, Morty. How do I get it to stop fast-forwarding?
不要这样 莫蒂 我怎么才能停止快进？
Morning, sweetie.
早上好 甜心
You wanna shower first?
你要先冲凉吗？
Yeah. No! I can't shower because then I'll fast-forward.
好 不！ 我不能冲凉 否则我就要快进了
And if I fast-forward, who knows how long I'll fast-forward for.
如果我快进了 谁知道我会快进到什么时候
How's this? I'm gonna rough it today, like in the Old West. Okay?
这个怎么样？ 今天会很顺利 就像穿着这个旧西式的衣服 对吧？
Donna, I wanna tell you what's going on right now so bad...
唐娜 我先告诉你刚才发生什么事情
...but it might lead to an argument. We can't argue because off I'll go.
但是这样我们就会吵架 我们不能 吵架 因为一吵架我就不见了
So just know there is a problem.
所以你知道这有点问题就行了
I tried to get rid of the problem, it almost ended up in my ass.
为这个我想了一整夜
I'm gonna go to work and try to figure this out.
我想就穿着这个去上班了
You're going to work in your bathrobe?
你准备穿着睡袍去上班？
Honey. We can't argue, okay? No more arguing.
宝贝 我们不能再吵架了 好吗？ 再也不能吵架
You're right. I'm wrong. All the time. You want a kiss?
都是我的错 好吗 要亲一下吗
I'll take a kiss. I can't. If I give you a kiss...
那就亲一下 不 我不能亲你因为我一亲你
...it might lead to something else, then... three minutes goes by.
那样会导致… 然后又是三分钟没了
You're laying there disappointed, I'm smiling.
之后你就又会失望地躺在那儿 而我在笑
I wanna be with you every minute of my life, that's why I gotta leave now.
我想跟你好好度过每一分钟 所以我得走了
Have a great day!
过得开心！
Once again, Michael left Donna in bed confused and unsatisfied.
又一次 唐娜迷茫地且失望地 坐在床上没有得到满足
Shut up, James Earl Jones!
闭嘴 詹姆斯・琼斯
No, you shut up, big mouth!
不 你闭嘴 大嘴巴！
Michael!
迈可！
Mr. Ammer is here
安莫先生在这儿
Your first day as a partner, you come to work in a fricking bathrobe?
作为合伙人第一天 你竟然穿着一身浴袍上班？
I did. I did.
是的是的
John, I just feel we should stop wasting our energy...
约翰 我只是觉得我们不该 把能量浪费在穿着
...on corporate brown-nosing and worrying who's got the better suit.
讨论谁的西装好看
Armani, Calvin Klein, who cares?
阿玛尼 CK 谁在乎？
Let's concentrate on what really matters, the work.
还是把精力集中在工作上
That's the craziest thing I've ever heard.
这是我听过的最疯狂的了
But goddamn it, you're right.
但他妈的你说得对极了
Life-changing. I feel freer.
改变生活 我感觉更自由了
Yeah... Keep the pants on.
裤子就别脱了
Sexual harassment, eh?
哦 性骚扰 对吗？
Speaking of life-changing...
说到改变生活
...there's something, or actually someone, I'd like to talk to you about.
有一件事 实际上是一个人 我要跟你谈谈
Janine. Everything okay?
洁宁 你们还好吗？
Michael, Janine and I decided to drop out of the rat race...
迈可 洁宁和我决定不再猫鼠赛跑
...slow down, move to Morocco.
放慢节奏 移居摩洛哥
Morocco? Morocco.
摩洛哥？ 摩洛哥
Okay.
好
Eric Lamensoff will assume my day-to-day responsibilities...
埃里克・兰邵夫将负责 我的日常事务
...and I'd like you to take his job.
你就做他现在的工作
But Eric Lamensoff is the head of the whole international division.
但是埃里克・兰邵夫是 整个国际部的头啊
I've been your partner one day. So?
我做你合伙人才一天 那有怎么样？
Every account you worked on turned into gold.
你的每个客户都成了金蛋
You know, I wouldn't be surprised...
如果有一天你成了CEO
...if one day you ended up being our CEO.
我不会吃惊的
Hey, I would love for that to happen, but...
嘿 我希望如此 但是
No! No, no, no! I don't want a promotion!
不！不 不 不！ 我不想升职
No!
不！
Michael, you have a phone call.
迈可 你的电话
Michael Newman.
迈可・纽曼
Word up, big guy.
怎么样 好家伙
Ten years ago you told me you wanted to be CEO.
10年前你告诉我你想成为CEO
Great news. Eric Lamensoff killed himself.
好消息 埃里克・兰邵夫自杀了
So you better stop with the junk food, Mr. Chairman...
所以别再吃垃圾食品了 主席先生
...or you'll end up killing yourself too.
要不你也会归西的
Opening virtual blinds.
打开虚拟窗帘
Ten years? How much worse can things get?
10年？ 那会变得有多遭？
Oh, my God, I'm a fat guy!
哦 我的上帝 我是只肥猪！
Look at me.
看看我
What is this? This is titties.
这是什么？ 这是乳头
I got juicy titties!
我有个奶头！
What... What is that?
这是什么？
Oh, God, no.
哦 上帝 哦
Just take me home.
我要回家
This is 1010 WINS news. February 5th, 2017.
这里是1010新闻 2017年2月5日
Britney Spears had her 23rd baby today.
小甜甜今天生下了她的第23个孩子
Proud father Kevin Federline says he's now considering getting a job.
她自豪的丈夫凯文・菲德兰说 他开始考虑找份工作
Also, Michael Jackson, the first man to clone himself...
迈可尔・杰克逊作为 第一个克隆自己的人
...is now suing himself for molesting himself.
正在控告他自己的克隆体 对他进行性骚扰
Donna!
唐娜！
Can I help you?
你是谁？
Hey, Dad. "Hey, Dad"?
嘿 爸爸 “嘿 爸爸”？
Ben? That's you?
本？ 是你吗？
Look how big you got. You're enormous.
看看你 长得这么肥
Look who's talking, Captain Twinkie of the S.S. Fat-Ass!
看看你自己 大屁股双胞胎舰长！
Really good for my self-esteem.
这对我树立自信心很有帮助
Maybe if you would take me to Pilates like you said...
也许你会带我去做普拉提
...people wouldn't think I was Rosie O'Donnell!
那样人们就不会把我当作 玫瑰・奥当劳
Come on, I love you!
过来 我爱你！
Bring me back the Twinkies! You're so cruel!
带我回去！ 你太残人了！
Will you please stop yelling? It is so embarrassing.
别嚷了行吗？ 太丢人了
Is that my daughter? Mom, I'm going to Derek's!
你是我女儿？ 妈 我去德里克家了！
That's you, Samantha? When did you get boobs?
萨曼塔？你什么时候长出胸部了？
The same time you did, Dad. Now can I go?
和你一起长的 我能走了吗？
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Who the hell's this Derek guy?
哇 哇 哇 谁是德里克？
My boyfriend, the hottest boy in school, hello?
我的男朋友 学校最热门的男孩 你不知道？
He's gonna be hot when I burn his house down.
我烧了他家他会更热门
Get your ass upstairs, put normal clothes on.
到楼上去 穿的正常点
Why are you so mean to me? Get them on now!
你怎么对我这么刻薄？ 给我去换了！
And wipe off all that makeup! Right!
把化妆都卸了！ 好吧！
Is Peanut dead too?
花生也死了？
This one's got the duck doing all the work.
这只可真是把鸭子物尽其用了
Donna. Donna.
唐娜 唐娜
Goddamn it.
该死
Look how gorgeous you look. I'm so scared.
你真漂亮 我很害怕
Knock, knock, gang. Hey, sweetie.
我过来了 嘿 亲爱的
What's going on?
发生什么了？
Donna and I were gonna get hot chocolate.
唐娜和我准备去吃热巧克力
You want us to bring you one? You cheating on me?
你要吗？ 你背叛了我？
With Johnny G-String over here?
和这个丁字裤家伙在一起？
Come on. Time-out. I thought we were past that.
好了 暂停 我以为我们已经解决这个问题了
No, no, no, we're past this argument. No, you're right, no big deal.
不 不 不 你是对的 没什么大不了
Hey, it's just that you don't mess with another man's wife!
你只不过是在搞别人的老婆！
Michael! Stop it! Stop it, Michael!
迈可！ 住手！ 住手迈可！
It was your decision to move out! So stay out!
是你自己的决定！ 别闹了！
Get off me! You sticking up for him?
放开我！ 你竟然帮他说话？
Go away! Go away, I hate you!
滚出去 滚出去 我恨你！
We can't argue! Donna, please! I hate you! I hate you!
我们不能吵架！ 唐娜 求你了！ 我恨你！我恨你！
Oh, man!
哦 不！
You hate me?
你恨我？
No. No.
不 不
Ten years, you're not finished yet?
10年了 你还没弄完？
Morty! Why did you do this to me?
莫蒂！ 为什么要这样对我？
You did this to yourself, Michael.
你自己干得  迈可
No. No, I didn't wanna waste all that time.
不不 我不想浪费那些时光
I didn't wanna lose Donna!
我不想失去唐娜！
The remote goes by your behavior.
那个遥控器是跟你的行为一致的
Every time you had a conflict between work and home, work won.
每次你的工作和家庭产生冲突的时候 总是工作占先
No, not true. Lie to your wife.
不 不是这样的 对你的老婆撒谎
Lie to yourself. But you cannot lie to the remote.
对你自己撒谎 但你不能对遥控器撒谎
The remote is lie-proof, so you can't change what already happened.
这个遥控器可以识别谎言 所以你不能改变已经发生的事
But you're still a young man.
但是你还是个年轻人
A young, fat man. You could win Donna back.
一个年轻的胖子 你可以把唐娜赢回来
So that's what I'll do.
我这就去
Go for it, tubs.
去吧 胖子
I saw what you did to the duck. Very good. Nice work.
你和鸭子干得不错 我看见了
You'll feel that in a second.
你马上就会感觉到的
All right, please, please just read my note.
求你了 看我的条子
Hate you! I hate you! I hate you!
我恨你 我恨你 我恨你！
Michael, are you awake?
迈可 你醒了吗？
Michael, honey. Are you awake?
迈可亲爱的 你醒了吗？
Donna.
唐娜
Where'd all my fat go?
我得脂肪哪儿去了？
It was just a dream? A terrible, terrible dream.
只是一个梦吗？一个糟透了的梦
What's that, Michael? You had a bad dream?
怎么了 迈可？ 做恶梦了？
Did a fuzzy dog push me over?
有只狗把我扑倒了是吗？
Oh, Shaggy the miracle dog?
哦 沙棘 那只神奇的狗？
Yeah, if he hadn't knocked you on your noggin...
是的 如果不是他把你扑倒了
...you wouldn't have had the CAT scan that found the cancer before it spread.
你就不会去做CT 就不会发现 你有癌症 还好没扩散
I have cancer?
我得癌症了？
No, you had cancer.
不 你曾经得了癌症
You're the only person to gain weight during chemo.
你是世界上唯一因化疗而增肥的人
That's probably what caused your heart attack.
结果导致心脏病发作
Heart attack?
心脏病？
I thought they weaned you off the morphine.
我记得他们已经停止使用吗啡了啊
Okay, Mr. Junk Food...
好了 快餐先生
...since the injury, you haven't been healthy a full day.
自从那次受伤以后 你就从没有一天健康
When exactly did I hurt my head?
我什么时候脑震荡的？
When was it? Like, six years ago?
什么时候？ 大概是6年前
Six more years! No! No! It skipped all my sickness.
又是6年！ 不！ 不！ 它跳过了我所有的病痛
I'm gonna ask them to cut back on painkillers.
我叫医生把止痛药停了
Donna, don't go.
唐娜 别走
What's this?
这是什么？
That's not bad for your third liposuction.
3次抽脂手术之后 这还算不错
One more tummy tuck should take care of it.
再来一次就行了
Oh, it looks like a tongue...
像个大舌头
...licking.
舔啊舔的
Look, I should go. Bill's waiting for me downstairs.
我得走了 比尔还在楼下等我
So I'll probably... Bill?
我得… 比尔？
You're still with Speedo Torpedo?
你还和那个斯比度・土批度在一起？
Whatever happened to "forever and ever," honey?
我们的“一生一世”呢 ？
"Forever and ever"?
“一生一世”？
Look, Michael, I'm trying to have a civilized relationship with you...
听着 迈可 为了孩子
...for the kids' sake.
我已经尽力维持我们的关系了
I really wanna be friends, but I can't do that if you...
我很想做朋友 但是…
Would you stop flapping that thing?
别再弄那玩意儿了行吗？
It's my flap, I'll do whatever the hell I want with it!
这是我的 我喜欢怎么弄就怎么弄！
You done?
完了吗？
Look, Bill's my husband.
比尔是我的丈夫
Please learn to accept that. I really have to go.
接受现实吧 我得走了
Husband? Donna?
丈夫？ 唐娜？
No. Donna. Donna. Donna!
不 唐娜 唐娜 唐娜！
Welcome to Newman Architecture.
欢迎来到纽曼建筑中心
Building a better world for all of us.
为大家创造更美好的世界
Architect of the year, 2018.
2018 最佳建筑师
All your dreams came true, huh, moron?
笨蛋 你所有的梦想都实现了
Dad. Hey, how you feeling?
爸爸 感觉怎么样？
Benjamin. Look at that. Look... What?
本杰明 看看 看什么？
Your face. Your skinny face. You're shaving now, huh, kid?
你漂亮的脸蛋 开始刮胡子了？
Your entire ass is gone. What happened? Good for you.
你的肥屁股不见了发生什么了？ 这样很好
Right, my ass. Why don't we talk about it in my office.
哦 我的屁股 去我的办公室谈谈
My old office.
我的老办公室
The architect. How did this happen?
嘿 建筑师 你怎么做到的？
Mom said you were still a little loopy. No, no, no. I'm feeling terrific.
妈妈说你还有一点晕晕的 不 不 不 我感觉好极了
The weight. How did you do it? Staple treatment like your old man?
你是怎么减肥的？ 和你老爸一样抽脂吗？
Wanna have a flap fight? You gotta see this...
想不想打肚皮仗？ 看看我的
No. Just working out with Bill five times a week. Same as always.
不是 我和比尔每周坚持5次健身
That's a looker. Blondie, big lips. Chesty.
真漂亮 金发 性感嘴唇 大胸部
Is that your girl?
你女朋友？
No, that's your daughter Samantha.
不 那是你女儿萨曼塔
Of course it is.
哦 是的
And you better always take care of her...
你得好好照顾她
...and make sure nobody touches her except you.
确保除了你之外没人敢碰她
Pop, I'm just getting ready for this meeting.
爸爸 我得开会了
Okay. Absolutely. I'll take off for you.
当然 我走了
I'd like to spend more time together. All of us.
我想我们在一起多花些时间聚聚
Take you out for ice cream. How's that?
一起出去吃冰激凌 怎么样？
I know your mother won't come...
我知道你妈妈不会来
...but you, Samantha, Grandpa, Grandma.
但是你 萨曼塔 爷爷 奶奶
That'd be nice, huh?
会很温馨的 对吗？
I knew something was funny with you today.
你今天有点怪怪的
Papa, take a seat. Let me get you a water, okay?
爸爸 坐着我给你倒杯水
What are we sitting for?
坐着干什么？
Here you go, Pop, drink this. All right. Drink some water.
来吧 喝点水 好吧 喝点
There, I had my water. What's going on?
好了 发生什么了？
Grandpa died, Dad.
爷爷死了 爸爸
He died a while back now.
有段时间了
No, no, no.
不 不
Don't say that.
别这么说
Where was I?
我在哪儿？
You're crying?
你哭了？
What happened?
发生什么了？
Nothing. You know, he just got old. That's life.
没什么 只是老了去世了
Shit. You're born and you live and you die.
该死 你出生 你生活 你死去
Man, I gotta go.
我得走了
Hey, hang on. Susie, push my next meeting.
嘿 等等 苏希 推迟我的会议
No, no, do your meeting. It's fine. I'm just dizzy.
不不 开会去 我只是有点晕
Why are you crying? I'm dizzy from the operation.
为什么要哭？ 我只还有点头晕
You're gonna make me cry, Dad. You don't... You don't have to go.
你弄得我也要哭了 爸爸 你用不着走
You look... You look good.
你看起来很好
It's all right. Goodbye.
没关系 再见
Come on.
来吧
It won't take you there.
它不会带你去的
Take me where?
带我去哪儿？
To the moment he died. You weren't there.
你爸爸死的时候你不在那
Of course I wasn't.
我当然不在
Can you take me to the last time I saw him, please?
带我去看看我最后和他见面的时候
Hey, Dad. Sorry to bug you.
嘿 很抱歉打搅你
Would you mind looking at my shopping mall design again?
再看看我的购物中心设计行吗？
This one is cheaper.
这个成本更低
But if you check this out...
但是你看这个
...you'll see it has a much better natural flow...
你会看到它更加的自然
Cheaper one, like I said. Now, just let me do my e-mail.
我说过更便宜的那个 我要弄邮件了
Yeah. Yeah, you're right, Dad.
是的 是的 你是对的
He ain't right. You're a schmuck! Look at it!
你这个笨蛋 这样不对 看啊！
Surprise.
惊喜
Hey, Grandpa.
嘿 爷爷
Oh, my God.
哦 我的上帝
When did you get so handsome?
怎么变得这么帅了？
So, Michael, I had a wonderful idea.
迈可 我有个很好的主意
Your mother's playing canasta with her friends tonight.
你妈和她朋友今晚打牌
I thought, "What a great opportunity."
我认为这是个好机会…
You, me and Ben should go and have a boys' night out.
你 我 本 我们可以去夜店
Can't. What do you mean you can't?
不行 不行是什么意思？
You have to eat sometime.
你总得吃饭吧
We could go, we could whistle at pretty girls.
我们可以去对着美女吹口哨
I'm down for that. See? He's down.
我想去 看到吗？ 他要去
I don't know what it means, but he's down.
我不知道那是什么意思 但是他说他要去
Hey. Please. Don't give me that finger.
嘿 别用那根手指
I'll make you a deal.
这样吧
If you come, I'll show you the quarter trick.
如果你来 我会给你表演硬币把戏
Will you look at the man? I'll tell you the secret.
你难道就不能看他一眼？ 我会告诉你把戏得秘密
No, Dad.
不 老爹
Don't you wanna know how I?
你不想知道吗？
I know how you do the stupid trick. I've always known.
我不要你的什么秘密 我早就知道了
Can you let me do my work?
你能让我专心工作嘛
You've always known.
你一直都知道
You're pathetic.
你真可悲
Okay.
好吧
I'm so sorry I barged in.
我很抱歉如此唐突
I love you, son.
我爱你 儿子
See you later, Grandpa, I love you.
待会见 爷爷 我爱你
Dad.
爸爸
I love you, son.
我爱你 儿子
I love you too, Dad.
我也爱你 爸爸
I'll miss you.
我会想你的
You know that.
你知道得
Goodbye.
再见
I'm sorry about your father.
你父亲的死 我很遗憾
Taking him wasn't something I wanted to do.
我并不想带走他
What do you mean "taking him"?
带走他？ 你是什么意思
I'm an angel, Michael.
我是个天使 迈可
An angel?
天使？
I thought an angel was supposed to protect people.
我以为天使是要保护人的
I'm the angel of death.
我是死亡天使
Your dad, it was his time.
你父亲 他的时辰到了
You bastard.
你这个狗娘养的
All right, leave me alone. Leave me alone.
别过来 别过来
You had your fun. Just take me to a good place.
你玩够了 带我去个好点的地方
And now, everybody, it's time for Mr. Newman to say a few words.
好了 各位现在让纽曼先生来说几句
Yay, Michael!
耶 迈可！
Go get them, Michael! Speech!
上吧 迈可！ 演讲！
Wedding cake. Wedding cake.
婚礼蛋糕 婚礼蛋糕
Okay, where's the groom? Show your face.
好 新郎在哪儿？ 让我看看
Hi, Dad.
嗨 爸爸
Ben. I didn't miss my son's wedding.
本 我没有错过我儿子的婚礼
Wow, this is terrific, buddy. Who's the lucky lady?
哇 太棒了 谁是幸运的女孩
Very funny, Mr. Newman.
很有趣 纽曼先生
Aunt Peggy, is that you?
佩蒂阿姨，是你吗？
God, you got old.
上帝 你老了
No, no. I... She... I'm just playing. She knows that.
不不 她知道我是开玩笑的
Ma.
妈妈
Ben's wife...
本的太太
...welcome to the family.
欢迎来到这个大家庭
Thank you.
谢谢
Congratulations. Let's have the best night, okay?
恭喜！大家好好玩！
Look at you, Ma. You look amazing.
妈妈 你太美了
Michael, you haven't kissed me like that since you were a little boy.
迈可 长大以后你就没亲过我
You are the best, Ma. You know I know that, right?
妈妈 你是最棒的 你知道嘛？
Oh, darling, that's so sweet.
哦 亲爱的 真好听
You know, Michael, your father would've loved to be here.
迈可 你父亲多么想见到这一天啊
I know, Ma.
我知道 妈妈
Okay? I'm just glad you're here.
我很高兴你能来
Me too, bubbala. Me too. Me too. It's beautiful. Beautiful.
我也是 太美了一切都太美了
Beautiful. Look at her.
看看她
Donna, my favorite.
唐娜 我最喜欢她
You're such a schmuck for letting her go.
你居然放她走了 真笨蛋
But don't let me ruin your evening. I'll talk to you later.
别让我毁了你的夜晚 晚点见
Christina.
克里斯蒂娜
Michael, you've been so generous taking care of all this...
迈可 你真慷慨
...and the kids' honeymoon.
包揽了他们的蜜月费
Absolutely. Thank you so much.
应该的 谢谢你
Of course. Ben's wife seems like a nice kid, huh?
她是个好孩子
I think she's wonderful. Definite keeper.
我觉得她棒极了 好极了
Here's one you might remember from The Cranberries.
接下来是“酸莓合唱团”
Out of all the songs, huh?
最棒的歌 不是嘛？
Bill, since it's our son's wedding...
比尔 这是我们的孩子的婚礼
...do you mind if I dance with my ex-husband for a minute?
你介意我和我的前夫跳只舞吗？
Not at all. Thank you.
不客气 谢谢
Just have her back by midnight, all right, champ?
午夜之前让她回来 行吗 冠军？
You got it, Bill.
你会的 比尔
Why does he have a bathing suit on?
他怎么不穿裤子？
Nice Speedo, buddy.
棒极了 史比杜
Still smelling good, huh?
还是这么香？
After all these years.
这么多年后
Are you happy?
高兴吗？
Of course I'm happy, our son just got married.
我当然高兴 我们的孩子结婚了
Not about that. Are you happy about where our lives ended up?
不是这个 是关于我们走到这地步？
"Ended." It's not over yet.
还没有结束呢
That's my Donna. It's true.
这才是我的唐娜 真的
That Samantha?
那是萨曼塔？
Hey. What are you doing? Put a sweater on. Cover them up.
嘿 你干什么？把胸部盖上
What is with you?
你怎么了？
Just kidding, I...
我开玩笑的
Just not used to seeing you all grown-up like this.
我还不习惯见你们都长这么大
Okay, well, if that's your way of telling me that I look pretty, then thank you.
如果这是你的恭维 谢谢
Let's go get some cake.
我们去吃点心
I'll race you there, Dad. Come on. Okay.
爸爸 我们比赛谁先到 好啊
"Dad"?
“爸爸”？
Michael, are you okay?
迈可 你还好吗？
Is there a doctor? We need a doctor here!
有医生吗？ 医生！
Michael!
迈可！
Dad! Dad!
爸爸！
It's just corn flakes.
只是麦片而已
One dance, you pop an artery.
跳一支舞 你的大动脉就破了
Why'd you make me waste my entire life?
为什么让我浪费了一生？
You were fast-forwarding through your life...
你在遇到我之前
...Iong before you ever met me.
已经快进了你的人生
You lived the life you chose, big shot.
你自己决定的你的人生
This is not the life I wanted.
这不是我想要的
It is.
它是
Looks like it is.
看起来是
Hey. You're up. How you feeling?
怎么样了？
I feel better now that you guys are here.
你们来了我感觉好多了
Samantha's been here like 36 hours straight.
萨曼塔守了36个小时了
She said she wouldn't leave the hospital until you woke up.
她说你不醒她就不走
Why'd you do that? Because. You're my father.
你为什么要这样做？ 因为你是我爸爸
I thought Bill was your father.
我以为比尔是你爸爸
I have two fathers.
我有两个爸爸
One of them told me he was gonna live till he was 200. Remember?
有个告诉我他能活200岁 记得吗？
You both really need to get some sleep.
你们俩都需要休息一下
And I got a plane to catch.
我还要赶飞机
Big Ben's gotta go on his honeymoon.
大本要去度蜜月了
Actually, I just canceled the honeymoon.
我可以取消
Kensington deal might fall through, so I gotta go do damage control.
金士顿的合同可能要黄 我要去善后
Julie and I can go to Italy anytime. No.
朱丽和我随时能去意大利 不
It's not that big a deal.
没什么大不了的
That's not fair to your wife. Dad...
这对你太太不公平 爸爸
...she gets it. Keeping the business going is more important.
她知道男人要以事业为重
Guys, I'm sorry. You're gonna have to leave. He needs his rest.
你们得走了 他需要休息
All right. Bye, Dad.
再见 爸爸
Bye, Daddy.
再见 爹的
Get this off of me.
把这些拿开
Whoa, whoa!
哇 哇哦！
Hey, fella, you're a long way from walking out of here.
你还不能下地呢
I gotta see my son.
我要见我的孩子
You're not going anywhere. Now, get back into the bed.
你哪儿不能去 回床上去
Isn't that Colin Farrell? Where?
那是克林・法瑞尔吗？ 哪儿？
Michael.
迈可
Those machines are keeping you alive.
这个机器让你活着
I gotta talk to my boy.
我的告诉我的孩子
Michael, stop. No.
迈可 停下 不
Michael, it doesn't have to end now.
迈可 没必要这么快结束
Ben!
本！
Dad? Dad?
爸爸？ 爸爸？
Dad, what are you doing?
爸爸 你这是干嘛？
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
Oh, my God. Help! Help!
哦 我的上帝 来人啊！来人啊！
Dad! Dad! Help!
爸爸！ 爸爸！ 来人啊！
Ben, Ben.
本 本
Family. Family. Family.
家庭 家庭 家庭
What?
什么？
Family. Family. Family comes first.
家庭 家庭 家庭第一
Family comes first.
家庭第一
Honeymoon. Honeymoon.
蜜月 蜜月
Honeymoon. I love you.
蜜月 蜜月 我爱你
Samantha. Samantha.
萨曼塔 萨曼塔
I didn't make 200, but I love you.
我没活到200岁 但是我爱你
I love you.
我爱你
Bill, Bill, Bill.
比尔 比尔 比尔
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
Michael.
迈可
The note you wrote her, it's in your pocket.
你的条子在口袋里
Forever and ever, babe.
一生一世 宝贝
It's time to go.
该走了
Where am I? You're in Bed Bath & Beyond, sir.
我在哪儿？ 你在超越商店
I was just watching you sleep.
我一直在看你睡觉
You looked like you were having a crazy dream.
你好像做了一个疯狂的梦
What?
什么？
You're not supposed to lay in the beds, but I do sometimes.
你不该躺在床上的 不过我有时候也这么做
I'm back in the store?
我回到商店了？
I'm young again. I'm young again.
我又年轻了 我又年轻了
Well, I mean, you're not "young" young.
我意思是你不是那么年轻
I'm young. You're kind of on the back nine.
不 我才年轻 你有点老了
No, no. No. I'm just teeing off, baby.
不不不 我只是…
Look at you.
看看你
You want a friend? You want a friend? I'll be your friend, baby.
你想要给朋友是吗？ 我会成你的朋友 宝贝
I'll be your friend. I'll be your...
我会成你的朋友
Oh, my God!
哦 我的上帝！
Yes, my crappy car!
我的破车！
You mediocre, middle-class piece of shit!
你这普普通通的中产阶级破车！
I love you!
我爱你！
Pop, Pop. Pop. There he is. There he is.
爸爸 爸爸 你还在
What's wrong? What happened? Nothing's wrong.
怎么了 出什么事了？ 没事
Everything's incredible, Ma. I just wanted to tell you I love you.
妈妈我只想告诉你我很爱你们
I love you. I love you so much.
我爱你 我很爱你
You gotta tell me how you do the quarter trick, it's driving me crazy.
你的硬币把戏把我搞疯了 告诉我
A magician never reveals his secrets.
魔法师不会透露秘密
However, if you invite us over for dinner more...
如果你邀请我的话…
You come over tomorrow night, and the night after that. Any time you want.
明天晚上就来 以后什么时候都可以
Stop, I'm gonna have a heart attack. No, I have the heart attacks.
住手 心脏病要犯了 不 我才有心脏病
Thank you so much for giving birth to me, I know it hurt. Okay?
谢谢你生下我 我知道那很痛
You have no idea. But, honey, please, stay off the bong pipe.
你不会知道的 宝贝 别吃那甜点
I can't promise you that.
我可不保证
Okay. I'm up.
好了 我醒了
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样？
If you massage me first.
如果你先给我按摩
Okay, let's go to sleep.
好吧 继续睡觉
Mom, wake up! There's a crazy noise downstairs.
妈妈 起来 楼下有声音
What the heck is going on?
搞什么飞机啊？
Hey, do you mind? I am trying to concentrate.
嘿 小声点行吗？ 我需要集中精力
Here I am, staying up all night...
我的熬夜
...trying to come up with activities for our Fourth of July camping trip...
为我们的国庆露营做准备
...but you won't let me think!
你都不给我机会想！
You want time to think? Why don't you think about the fact that you just wo...
你需要时间想？ 你为什么不多…
What did you just say?
你刚才说什么？
Yes, you heard me. If you keep up this weird attitude...
你听到了 如果你继续这样的态度…
...I won't be able to work for a year and have to plan 10 more vacations.
我没法在1年里设计10次假期
That make you happy? Did you eat a bad Yodel?
高兴吗？ 你是不是吃错药了？
Give me those big lips.
我亲亲你性感的嘴
What's going on down here? Ben. Ben!
怎么了？ 本 本！
Come here. Oh, my God.
过来 我的上帝
I missed you, I missed you. Look at you, boy.
我想你 我想你 看看你 大男孩
I'm gonna finish the tree house. We're gonna sleep in it next weekend.
我马上弄完树屋 咱们下周就上去睡觉
From now on, we're gonna exercise and I'm not gonna wear a Speedo.
从今天开始我们一起健身
All right! All right.
好啊！ 好啊
And you. Nice jump! I love you.
跳得漂亮！ 我爱你
One day, you are gonna be the hottest chick alive.
有一天 你会成为最火辣的女孩
But you still gotta have brains.
但你还得有头脑
So tomorrow I'm gonna teach you calculus.
明天我要教你微积分
You know calculus?
你懂微积分？
I knew you'd call me on that. Your mom will teach you.
好吧被你看穿了 让你妈教你吧
Now, get your rest, because tomorrow we're going camping!
快去睡觉 我们明天要去露营！
I know! It's gonna be the best!
我知道！ 那会是最棒的！
Put a sweater on! Don't take it off! Okay, Daddy.
衣服穿好 不准脱！ 好 爸爸
Oh, and Sundance!
哦 阳阳！
Doggie years go by very quick, so it's time to enjoy the real thing.
你该享受一下真家伙了
Yeah, go get some, baby.
去吧 宝贝
What are you doing? What are you doing?
你在干什么？
No. Go to Sundance, not the duck.
不 是阳阳 不是鸭子
They told me at the pet store it was a female.
宠物店说她是母狗
They lied to me, I guess.
看来我上当了
You staying downstairs tonight? Why? That's getting you going?
你今晚在楼下过？ 你想怎么？
It's Fourth of July, I'm gonna celebrate with my wife.
国庆日 我应该和老婆好好庆祝
Take my time, massage her, make sure she is fully satisfied.
慢慢来 先按摩 让她充分得到满足
But you know, it isn't the Fourth of July, it's only the second.
今天不是国庆 国庆是昨天
That's even better. Happy second of July, honey.
那就庆祝国庆第二天吧
Think I like this holiday. Yeah?
我喜欢这节日 恩？
I'm gonna go change into my Pocahontas costume.
我会换上我的“风中奇缘”装扮
I'll see you upstairs. I'll bring the duck.
楼上见 我会带鸭子上来
Okay, I gotta call my dad and tell him to get the old tent ready.
我叫老爸把帐篷准备好
"Like I said, 'Good guys need a break.'
“象我说的 好人该有好运”
I know you'll do the right thing this time.
你这次会做正确的选择
Love, Morty.
爱你的 莫蒂
P. S:
附注：
Your wife's rocking body still drives me crazy."
你老婆真火辣 我快疯了
Okay, Morty.
好的 莫蒂
Hey, who wants to have a pillow fight?
嘿 谁想打枕头仗？